[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50, Introduction
大卫·马兰：好的 这是CS50 介绍
to Programming with Python.
用Python编程
My name is David Malan, and this is our week on library.
我叫大卫·马兰 这是我们的图书馆周
So libraries are generally files of code that other people
所以库通常是其他人
have written that you can use in your own programs or a library's code
你可以在你自己的程序或库的代码中使用
that you've written that you can use in your own program,
你可以在你自己的程序中使用
but maybe not just this program, but another and another as well.
但也许不仅仅是这个项目 还有其他的项目
So Python supports exactly this idea.
Python支持这个想法
This ability to share code with others, share code across your own projects.
这种与他人共享代码的能力 在您自己的项目中共享代码
And it does so by way of what it calls module.
它是通过所谓的模块来实现的
A module in Python is just a library that
Python中的模块只是一个库
typically has one or more functions or other features built into it.
通常具有内置于其中的一个或多个功能或其它特征
Generally, the purpose of a library or a module
通常 库或模块的用途
specifically is to encourage reusability of code
特别是鼓励代码的可重用性
if you find yourself using the same types of functions again and again,
如果你发现自己一次又一次地使用相同类型的函数
the same functionality.
相同的功能
If you find yourself copying and pasting from an old project
如果您发现自己从旧项目复制和粘贴
into your new project, odds are there's an opportunity there to factor out
在你的新项目中 很有可能有机会
that code that you keep copying and pasting that you keep reusing and put
你不断复制和粘贴的代码 你不断重复使用
it into a library that you can then load into your programs moving forward
你可以将它加载到你的程序中
so as to not just copy and paste it and have
这样我们就不需要复制粘贴
all these different copies all over.
到处都是不同的副本
So what are some of the modules or libraries that Python comes with?
那么Python自带的模块或库有哪些呢？
Well, Python comes with a random library literally,
Python自带一个随机库
which is to say that when you install the Python
也就是说 当你安装Python
interpreter on your Mac or PC or somewhere
您的Mac或PC或其他地方的翻译器
in the cloud, not only do you get Python,
在云中 你不仅可以得到Python
you get a whole bunch of modules as well.
你也会得到一大堆模块
Now, these modules provide you with functions
这些模块为您提供了
that you don't have access to just by default like you do print and input.
你不能像打印和输入一样默认访问它们
Print and input and other such functions just work in Python.
打印和输入以及其他类似的功能在Python中都可以工作
But sometimes functions are tucked away in these modules,
但有时功能隐藏在这些模块中
so you have to be more deliberate about loading them
所以你必须更仔细地装载它们
into the computer's memory.
存入计算机的内存
So somewhere on the computer's hard drive, once you've installed Python,
所以 在电脑硬盘上的某个地方 一旦你安装了Python
there is also, it turns out a file, probably called random.py
还有一个文件 很可能是随机文件.py
that someone else wrote probably long ago but that you have access to.
可能是别人很久以前写的 但你有权访问
And in that random.py file, there's probably one or more functions
在随机的.py文件中 可能有一个或多个函数
that you yourself can use in order to do things randomly.
你自己可以用来做随机的事情
That is to say how could you flip a coin in a program in Python?
这就是说 你怎么能在一个用Python编写的程序中抛硬币呢？
How could you pick a random number between 1 and 10 in Python?
在Python语言中 如何选择1到10之间的随机数？
Well, you need a bit of randomness.
嗯 你需要一点随机性
And while you could figure out mathematically
虽然你可以从数学上算出
how to write functions like that yourself,
如何自己编写这样的函数
it's a lot easier to stand on the shoulders of others who've already
站在别人的肩膀上要容易得多
solved that problem for you so you can focus on the problem
为你解决了那个问题 这样你就可以专注于这个问题了
that you yourself want to solve.
你自己想要解决的问题
So for documentation on most any Python module,
因此 有关几乎所有Python模块的文档
you go to the official Python docs.
你可以去看官方的Python文档
And you go to a URL like this where the documentation for that specific module
您可以转到这样的URL 其中包含该特定模块的文档
lives.
活着
And within the documentation, you'll see a list
在文档中 您将看到一个列表
of the functions or other functionality that some module provide.
某些模块提供的功能或其他功能
But how do you go about loading a module into your own program
但是 如何将模块加载到您自己的程序中呢
so that you can use the functions in that module?
以便您可以使用该模块中的函数？
Well, we need a new keyword in Python and namely it's import.
那么 我们需要在Python中使用一个新的关键字 即它的导入
The import keyword in Python allows you to import the contents of the functions
使用Python中的IMPORT关键字可以导入函数的内容
from some module in Python.
来自Python语言中的某个模块
Well, how might I go about using this in practice?
那么 我该如何在实践中使用它呢？
Well, let me propose that there exists in that random module
好吧 让我假设在随机模块中存在
this function among others.
在其他功能中 这一功能
So I have copied and pasted from the documentation
所以我从文档中复制并粘贴了
this summary of a function called Choice.
这是一个名为Choice的函数的摘要
Now, the function exists in the random module, so to speak,
现在 这个函数存在于随机模块中 可以这么说
not a random module, the random module.
不是随机模块 是随机模块
And so generally the documentation describes it fully like this.
因此 一般来说 文档完全是这样描述的
random.choice is how you would technically call this function,
随机选择是您从技术上调用此函数的方式
though, we'll see alternatives to that.
我们会看到其他的替代方案
In parentheses, there is a parameter called S-E-Q for sequence.
在括号中 有一个名为S-E-Q的参数表示序列
And sequence generally means a list or something
序列一般是指一个列表之类的东西
that is list-like if you have a list of numbers or strings or anything else.
如果你有一个数字或字符串或其他任何东西的列表 它就像列表一样
And the documentation elaborate.
以及详细的文件
Well, how can I go about using this function to solve, perhaps,
那么 我该如何使用这个函数来解决 也许
a familiar problem?
一个熟悉的问题？
Well, let me go ahead and open up VS Code here.
好吧 让我在这里打开VS Code
And let me propose that we implement a program that simulates flipping a coin.
让我建议我们实现一个程序来模拟抛硬币
A coin that in the US has heads or tails, the idea of which
在美国 硬币有正面或反面
is to pick a decision with 50/50 probability.
是选择一个概率为50/50的决策
50% probability of heads, 50% probability of tails.
正面和反面各占一半
Or you can use some other mechanism like that.
或者你可以使用其他类似的机制
Well, let me go ahead and open a program with code called generate.py
好的 让我打开一个代码为generate.py的程序
because I want to start generating a whole bunch of random information.
因为我想开始生成一大堆随机信息
The first of which is just going to be a coin toss.
第一个就是抛硬币
Now, how do I go about using that function?
那么 如何使用该功能呢？
Well, I first have to import the random library.
首先 我必须导入随机库
So literally the first or among the first lines of my file
所以我的文件的第一行
should be import random.
应该是随机导入
And that just gives me access to all of the functions in that specific module.
这样我就可以访问这个特定模块中的所有功能
Now, suppose I want to flip a coin.
现在 假设我想抛硬币
Well, I can do random.choice per the documentation a moment ago.
嗯 我可以根据刚才的文档做随机选择
And that again takes a sequence.
这也需要一个序列
What's a sequence?
什么是序列？
It's a list or something that's list-like.
这是一个列表或类似列表的东西
And we know about lists.
我们知道名单
We've used lists to iterate over numbers.
我们用列表来排列数字
We've used lists to iterate over students at Hogwarts.
我们用名单来筛选霍格沃茨的学生
Let's go ahead now and iterate over just a list of two sides of a coin,
让我们继续讨论一个硬币的两面
"heads," quote, unquote, or tails.
“正面” 引号 引号 或反面
Now, I could call these anything I want.
现在 我可以把这些东西叫做任何我想要的东西
These are my string.
这是我的绳子
I just want to simulate a tossing a coin.
我只想模拟抛硬币
So I'm just going to say in all lowercase, heads and tail.
所以我只想说正面和反面
But notice the syntax.
但请注意语法
I have "heads" and "tails" in double quotes.
我把“正面”和“反面”用双引号引起来了
That's because they're strings.
那是因为它们是弦
I could also use single quotes so long as I'm consistent.
我也可以使用单引号 只要我始终如一
There's a comma between them, which means the list has two elements.
它们之间有一个逗号 这意味着列表有两个元素
They're square brackets to the right and the left, which
它们是左边和右边的方括号
indicates that this is indeed a list.
表示这确实是一个列表
That's the syntax recall for defining a list in Python.
这是在Python中定义列表的语法回想
And then lastly, there's something more familiar.
最后 还有一些更熟悉的东西
There's the parentheses outside of those square brackets.
这些方括号外面有圆括号
But those are just the parentheses that belong to the Choice function
但这些只是属于Choice函数的括号
and specify where its parameter gets passed in.
并指定其参数传入的位置
But again, unlike past function, I have to specify what module
但同样 与过去的函数不同 我必须指定哪个模块
this function is in at least for now.
这一功能至少目前是可行的
And so I do random.choice to call the specific function.
所以我随机选择来调用特定的函数
All right, well, it's one thing to flip a coin picking between those
好吧 好吧 在这两者之间抛硬币是一回事
with 50% probability.
概率为50%
And that's what random.choice does.
这就是随机选择的作用
It takes in a list, and it returns to one of those values randomly
它接受一个列表 并随机返回到其中一个值
with equal probability.
概率相等
Because I've passed in two items, I've got a 50/50 chance.
因为我通过了两个项目 所以我有50%的机会
If I passed in three items, it'd be a 33% chance for each of those items
如果我通过了三个项目 那么每一个项目都有33%的可能性
and so forth.
以此类推
Python does the math for you.
Python为您做了计算
But I want to store the value of this in a variable.
但是我想把它的值存储在一个变量中
So let's define a variable called coin equals whatever the return value is.
所以让我们定义一个变量 称为Coin Equals 不管返回值是什么
So this is indeed like flipping a coin.
因此 这确实就像抛硬币一样
I'm going to store in a variable called coin, whatever
我将存储在一个名为Coin的变量中 不管是什么
that value is, heads or tails.
这个值是 正面或反面
And now, just so I can see what's going on, let's go ahead
现在 为了让我知道发生了什么 让我们继续
and print out the value of that string coin
并打印出那枚字符串硬币的价值
All right, let me go ahead now and run this program in my terminal window.
好了 现在让我继续在我的终端窗口中运行这个程序
Python of generate.py, Enter.
PythonofGenerate.py 回车
And it looks like the first coin toss was the heads.
而且看起来第一个掷硬币的是人头
Let's go ahead and run it again.
让我们继续 再运行一次
And it looks like it was heads again.
而且看起来又是正面的
Maybe you want to chime into the chat here.
也许你想在这里加入我们的聊天
If I run it a third time, what's it going to be this time?
如果我第三次运行它 这一次会是什么？
If you want to type your thoughts in the chat,
如果你想在聊天中输入你的想法
you might think there's a bug here.
您可能会认为这里面有漏洞
But this is probability in action.
但这是行动中的可能性
If I go ahead and hit Enter a third time there,
如果我继续第三次按回车键
it's actually now tails And again, tails and again tails and again tails
实际上现在是反面 反面
and again tails and again heads.
一次又一次反面 又一次正面
Now, if we did this an infinite number of times,
现在 如果我们这样做无数次
it would indeed work out to be 50/50.
这确实会是50/50的结果
If we only do it a few times, it might not work out as cleanly.
如果我们只做几次 结果可能不会那么干净利落
But that's how probabilities indeed work.
但这就是概率的工作原理
All right, so I've got that now working.
好了 我现在把它弄好了
Could I have implemented this in a different way?
我可以用一种不同的方式来实现这一点吗？
Well, let me show you an alternative to actually using the import keyword alone
那么 让我向您展示一种单独使用IMPORT关键字的替代方法
and let me introduce the keyword from in Python.
让我来介绍一下在Python中的关键字from
So from is a keyword in Python that you can use when importing functions
因此 From是可在导入函数时使用的Python中的关键字
from a module, but it allows you to be a little more specific than import alone.
来自一个模块 但它允许您比单独导入更具体一些
So if I go back to my code here, it's worth
因此 如果我回到我的代码 它是值得的
noting that what technically I'm doing here by importing random
注意到从技术上讲 我在这里通过导入随机
is I'm technically importing everything that's in that module.
从技术上讲 我是在导入那个模块中的所有东西
So not just the function called random.choice but a few other functions
因此 不只是这个名为随机选择的函数 还有其他几个函数
as well.
也是
So instead of using this line of code at the top of my file,
因此 与其在我的文件顶部使用这行代码
import random, which will technically give me access
导入随机 从技术上讲 这将允许我访问
to all of the contents they're in, a downside of that
对于他们所在的所有内容 一个不利的方面是
is that I have to type in random.choice, random.this,
我必须输入随机的 选择 随机的 这个
random.that because all of the functions I'm calling
随机性 因为我调用的所有函数
have to be associated with the scope of that module.
必须与该模块的范围相关联
Well, suppose that I just want to call the function as its name, choice.
好的 假设我只想调用函数作为它的名称 CHOICE
I can do that as well.
我也可以这么做
Let me replace this first line here with from random import choice.
让我将这里的第一行替换为来自随机导入选择
And what this does effectively is it loads the function's name choice
这样做的有效作用是加载函数的名称选择
into my current namespace into the scope of the file I'm working in.
放到我当前命名空间中 放到我正在处理的文件的作用域中
What that means is that I now no longer have to specify
这意味着我现在不再需要具体说明
which choice function I mean.
我指的是哪种选择功能
I can just say choice.
我只能说选择
And so it loads it into the local namespace
因此 它将其加载到本地命名空间中
that is into my local vocabulary, if you will, so I can just now say choice.
这是我的本地词汇 如果你愿意的话 所以我现在可以说选择
This might be advantageous in what cases, do you think?
你认为这在什么情况下可能是有利的？
When might you want to import the name of the function explicitly like this
您可能希望在什么时候像这样显式导入函数的名称
as opposed to just saying random.choice--
而不是说是随机的 选择--
random.choice throughout your code when calling a function?
在调用函数时在代码中进行随机选择吗？
Any instincts here for this alternative import using from?
对于使用from的替代导入 这里有什么直觉吗？
AUDIENCE: Hello, I'm Mohammed Omar from Egypt.
观众：大家好 我是来自埃及的穆罕默德·奥马尔
And maybe if we have a variable that its name is basically like choice
也许如果我们有一个变量 它的名字基本上就像Choose
if I have a variable called the choice.
如果我有一个叫做选择的变量
So I need to differentiate which trays I choose.
因此 我需要区分我选择的托盘
So I'm going to choose random data choice.
所以我会选择随机数据选择
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good instincts.
大卫·马兰：是的 非常好的直觉
By using the first approach by just importing random,
通过使用仅导入随机的第一种方法
you're making sure that all of its contents
你要确保它的所有内容
are associated with or scoped to the random module
与随机模块相关联或被限定为随机模块的范围
so that you can have your own choice function.
这样你就可以有自己的选择功能了
You can have your own choice variable.
您可以有自己的选择变量
You can use the same names as all of the functions or variables that
您可以使用与所有函数或变量相同的名称
are stored inside of that file without them colliding, so to speak.
都存储在该文件中 而不会发生冲突
And this is a good thing.
这是一件好事
In older languages, it was the case that if you imported someone's library,
在更老的语言中 情况是这样的 如果你导入某人的库
you better hope that you're not using the same functions
您最好希望您使用的不是相同的函数
or variables as they are because you might
或变量本身 因为您可能
in fact have some kind of conflict.
实际上存在着某种冲突
Python and certain other languages allow you
Python和某些其他语言允许您
to scope the names of those functions and variables to the file or the module
将这些函数和变量的名称限定为文件或模块
that they come from.
他们来自哪里
So that's a good thing.
所以这是一件好事
But honestly, this is such a short program.
但老实说 这是一个如此短的程序
Or equivalently, maybe I'm using the choice function
或者等同地 也许我使用的是选择函数
in so many places calling random.choice, random.choice, random.choice.
在如此多的地方 人们都叫随机 选择 随机 选择
It's just making my code longer and longer and longer.
这只会让我的代码越来越长
Marginally so, but hey, just getting ugly and annoying,
有点像 但嘿 只是变得又丑又烦
I can simply import choice and now tighten up my code a little bit.
我可以简单地导入选项 现在稍微收紧我的代码
So as with so many decisions in the past,
因此 就像过去的许多决定一样
there's not necessarily one right approach or another.
不一定只有一种正确的方法
It depends.
看情况
But I think for those very reasons, sometimes
但我认为正是因为这些原因有时候
it's better to do what we did the first time, which
最好还是像我们第一次那样
is only import the module so as to retain the scope therein.
只是导入模块以保留其中的作用域
Well, let me propose that we transition to another function that
好吧 让我建议我们过渡到另一个功能
comes with Python's random module.
Python的random模块
And that's this here from the documentation randint.
这是从档案里找到的
It's a bit hard to say, but it implies get back a random int.
这有点难说 但它意味着返回一个随机整数
And if you read the documentation, it's a random int that's between A and B
如果你读了文档 它是一个介于A和B之间的随机整数
inclusive.
内d
So if you were to pass in 1 for A and 10 for B,
所以如果你把A的1分和B的10分都算进去
you would get back a number between 1 and 10 inclusive, including the 1
你会得到一个介于1和10之间的数字 包括1
and including the 10 potentially.
并包括潜在的10个
Each with a 10% probability.
每一个都有10%的可能性
So how might I go about using a program like this?
那么我该如何使用这样的程序呢？
Well, let me come back to my generate the py file.
好 让我回到生成py文件的过程
And why don't we go ahead and try generating
为什么我们不继续尝试
a random number between 1 and 10?
1到10之间的随机数
You might do this frequently in the real world.
在现实世界中 你可能经常这样做
When you just want someone to pick a random number,
当你只是想让某人随便选一个数字
you tell them as much in the human response.
你在人类的反应中也会告诉他们同样的信息
Let's get the computer to do the same here.
让我们让电脑在这里做同样的事情
Let me go ahead and delete my two lines of code at the bottom
让我继续删除我在底部的两行代码
but keep my import random.
但我的导入要随机
And let's go ahead and define a variable this time called number,
接下来我们定义一个变量 叫做number
set it equal to the return value of random.randint
将其设置为random.randint的返回值
and now passing A, a value of 1 and B, a value of 10.
现在传递A 值为1 B 值为10
And now, let's go ahead and print the number.
现在 让我们继续打印号码
I'm going to go ahead in my terminal window
我会在终端窗口
and run Python of generate.py and hit Enter.
运行generate.py的Python并按Enter键
4.
4.
A Python of generate.py and hit Enter.
一个generate.py的Python 然后按Enter
8, again, 9, again, 7, again, 10, again, 2, again.
8 再来 9 再来 7 再来 10 再来 2 再来
And we can do this all day long.
我们可以一整天都这样
And if we add all of those up, they should end up
如果我们把所有这些加起来
being with 10% probability each.
都有10%的概率
Now, how might you use this information?
那么 你会如何使用这些信息呢？
Well, maybe we're playing a guessing game.
好吧 也许我们在玩猜谜游戏
Or maybe we're trying to randomize the behavior of some character in the game.
或者 也许我们正试图将游戏中某个角色的行为随机化
You can imagine using very simple building blocks like this just
您可以想象使用像这样非常简单的构建块
spicing up your program by getting it to do things
通过让程序做一些事情来增加程序的趣味性
a little less predictably because you're choosing these values seemingly
更难预测 因为您似乎选择了这些值
randomly.
随机的
And you're deferring to Python to actually do
而你要推迟到Python来做实际的事情
the generation of these numbers using its own algorithms and its own math.
这些数字的产生使用它自己的算法和它自己的数学
Well, what more could we do here?
那么 我们在这里还能做些什么？
Let me propose that we introduce another function that
让我建议我们引入另一个函数
comes from this random library.
来自这个随机图书馆
Yet, another that you yourself don't have to implement, shuffle.
然而 另一个你自己不需要实现的东西 就是洗牌
If you read the documentation for shuffle in the same random module,
如果您阅读了同一随机模块中的Shuffle文档
you'll see that it takes in a list, for instance, of values
例如 您将看到它包含一个值列表
and just shuffles them up.
然后就把它们洗掉
It randomize them like a deck of cards.
它就像一副扑克牌一样让他们随机化
Here, you might shuffle them so as to put them into seemingly random order.
在这里 你可能会把它们打乱 让它们看起来像是随机排列的顺序
Well, how do I use this based on this function's name?
那么 根据这个函数的名称 我如何使用它呢？
Well, let me propose that we go back to VS Code here.
好吧 让我建议我们回到这里的VS代码
And let me go ahead and this time do the following.
让我继续下去 这一次做以下事情
Because I need to shuffle something like a deck of cards,
因为我需要洗牌之类的东西
let me go ahead and not just import random.
让我继续下去 而不仅仅是随机导入
But let me give myself a variable called cards that's going to be of type list.
但让我给自己一个名为Cards的变量 它的类型是List
And just so I have something to shuffle, I
为了让我有东西要洗牌 我
don't need all 52 cards in a typical deck.
不需要在典型的一副牌中包含所有52张牌
I'm just going to shuffle three cards.
我要洗三张牌
A Jack, a Queen, and a King.
一个杰克 一个王后和一个国王
I could call those strings anything I want,
我可以随心所欲地叫这些琴弦
but I just wanted a list of some values so as to shuffle them up.
但我只是想要一些值的列表 以便将它们打乱
That is randomize the order therein.
这就是将其中的顺序随机化
Well, how does this now work?
那么 现在这是怎么运作的呢？
If you read the documentation for random.shuffle,
如果您阅读随机洗牌的文档
you'll see that it shuffles the argument in place.
你会看到它把论据打乱了
That is unlike many of the functions we have seen.
这与我们看到的许多功能不同
It doesn't return to you a value that contains
它不会返回包含以下内容的值
the shuffled cards in this case.
在这种情况下洗过的牌
It actually shuffles the list it's given itself.
实际上 它会对自己给出的清单进行洗牌
So what this means for my code is that I need
所以这对我的代码意味着我需要
to do something like this-- random.shuffle
做这样的事情--随机的.洗牌
and pass in the variable containing those cards.
并传入包含这些卡片的变量
And then on a final line here, how might I go about printing the cards?
然后在这里的最后一行 我应该如何开始打印卡片？
Well, I could do this, and I could say print card.
嗯 我可以这么做 我可以说打印卡片
But if I do that, I'm actually going to see Python syntax for lists.
但如果我这样做了 我实际上会看到列表的Python语法
And it's just going to format in its own way using commas and the like.
它只是以自己的方式 使用逗号和类似的东西来格式化
I want to print these cards out one at a time
我想把这些卡片一次打印出来一张
just because I think it'll look a little better so we can use some of our syntax
只是因为我认为它看起来会更好一点 这样我们就可以使用我们的一些语法
from loops and say something like this--
从循环中说出这样的话--
for card in cards, go ahead and print out the current card.
对于卡片中的卡片 请继续打印当前卡片
So what's now happening here?
那么 这里现在发生了什么？
Line three, I'm defining a list of three cards in this order--
第三行 我按照这个顺序定义了三张牌的列表--
Jack, Queen, King.
杰克 王后 国王
I'm then shuffling those same cards on line four.
然后我在4号线上洗同样的牌
And then on line five, I'm using a for loop
然后在第五行 我使用了一个for循环
for each of the cards in that list printed out one at a time
对于该列表中的每张卡片 一次打印出一张
and because I'm using print one line at a time.
而且因为我一次打印一行
Well, let's see the results.
好了 让我们来看看结果
Down here in my terminal window, I'm going
在我的终端窗口里 我要去
to run Python of generate.py and hit Enter.
运行genate.py的Python并按Enter键
Queen, King, Jack seemingly shuffled because that's not
王后 国王 杰克似乎拖着脚步 因为那不是
the order I defined earlier.
我之前定义的顺序
Let's do it again.
我们再来一次吧
Queen, King, Jack.
皇后 金 杰克
Hmm, OK, that happens to be the same.
嗯 好吧 那正好是一样的
But let's see.
但让我们来看看
This could just be bad chance.
这可能只是个坏机会
There we go.
我们走吧
Jack, Queen, King.
杰克 王后 国王
Doesn't look like it's shuffled, but at least
看起来不像是洗牌的 但至少
we're getting back different orderings now.
我们现在得到了不同的订单
Again, Jack, Queen, King.
再说一次 杰克 王后 国王
Hmm, not so good.
嗯 不太好
Jack, Queen, King.
杰克 王后 国王
Not so good.
不怎么好
This is someone you probably want to play against with cards.
这是一个你可能想和他打牌的人
Queen, Jack, King, there we go.
皇后 杰克 金 我们走吧
But of course, we only have three cards here.
当然 我们这里只有三张卡
So there's not that many permutations we might see.
所以我们可能不会看到那么多的排列
And if we do this over time, we will see all of them.
如果我们随着时间的推移这样做 我们会看到他们所有的人
But if we had, of course, 13 or 52 cards,
当然 如果我们有13或52张卡片
we'd see a lot more permutations instead.
相反 我们会看到更多的排列
So we have now these three ways to generate random information.
所以我们现在有三种方法来产生随机信息
One, a simple coin toss if you want to start some kind of athletic event.
第一 如果你想开始某种运动项目 就简单地掷硬币
One, pick a number between 1 and 10 if you
第一 在1到10之间选一个数字
want to decide something based on that.
想以此为基础做决定
And now, using shuffle, we can even take in a list of things
现在 使用shuffle 我们甚至可以接收一个列表
and shuffle them about so that we get some kind of random behavior.
然后把它们打乱 这样我们就得到了某种随机的行为
Well, let me pause here and see if where there's
好吧 让我在这里暂停一下 看看是否有
any questions yet on random, on modules, or any of these three functions.
关于随机数、模块或这三个函数中的任何一个的任何问题
AUDIENCE: Yeah, can we increase or decrease
观众：是的 我们可以增加或减少
the probability of cards if we want to?
如果我们想的话 我们可以计算出卡片的概率
For example, there are three.
例如 有三个
There is a 33% chance of probable B. So is there
有33%的可能性是B 那么有没有
any chance to increase or decrease the probability?
有没有可能增加或减少概率
DAVID MALAN: Can you set these probabilities
大卫·马兰：你能把这些概率
not using these same functions?
不使用相同的功能？
Can you set the probabilities?
你能设定概率吗？
But you can absolutely implement some of your own functions
但是你完全可以实现一些你自己的功能
or use more sophisticated functions that do exist in this library and others
或者使用这个库和其他库中存在的更复杂的函数
to exercise more control.
来行使更多的控制权
These are meant to be very user-friendly and simple functions, certainly
这些都是非常用户友好和简单的功能 当然
the ones we looked at, that give you equal probability for all of those.
我们所看到的 所有这些的概率都是相等的
But absolutely you could skew things, though, hopefully,
但你绝对可以歪曲事实 尽管如此 希望
if you're implementing a gambling game or the like,
如果你正在实现一个赌博游戏或类似的游戏
you're not actually making some cards more probable than others.
你并不是真的让某些牌比其他牌更有可能
Allow me to turn back now to our implementation here of this randomness
现在让我回到我们在这里实现的随机性
and consider how we might leverage other types of functionality that
并考虑如何利用其他类型的功能
aren't necessarily in this specific library here.
并不一定在这个图书馆里
Well, it turns out that Python also comes with a statistics library.
好吧 事实证明 Python还附带了一个统计库
And this contains all sorts of functions for doing
它包含了各种各样的功能
things more statistical in nature, namely calculating
更具有统计性质的东西 即计算
means or medians or modes or other aspects of a data set
数据集的均值、中位数、众数或其他方面
that you might want to analyze.
你可能想分析一下
So how might we use the statistics module in Python?
那么我们如何使用Python中的统计模块呢？
Well, we might first just take a look at it's documentation
好吧 我们可以先看看它的文档
like any other module in Python.
就像Python中的其他模块一样
And we'll see within that library that there's a whole bunch of function.
我们会看到在这个库中有一大堆函数
And one of those functions is one that's quite simple.
其中一个功能非常简单
It's average.
很一般
A function that allows you to calculate the average of some numbers
一个函数 允许您计算一些数字的平均值
that you've passed in.
你已经通过了
Let me go ahead and in VS Code in my terminal window, open up a new file
让我在终端窗口的VS Code中打开一个新文件
called average.py.
名为average.py
And at the top of this file, I'm going to import
在这个文件的顶部 我将导入
a different library this time, namely the statistics module in Python.
这一次是一个不同的库 即Python中的统计模块
And now, I'm going to go ahead and call a function that I know comes
现在 我将继续调用一个函数
in that module, namely mean for the average of some values.
在该模块中 即用于某些值平均值
And I'm going to call statistics.mean.
我要打电话给南极洲
And I'm going to pass into this function mean, a list of some values.
我将传入这个函数mean 一个值的列表
And let's suppose that I'm quickly trying
假设我很快地
to calculate what my current grade average is in school.
来计算我目前在学校的平均成绩
And I did really well on my first test.
我第一次考试考得很好
And I got 100%.
我得到了100%
And on my second, I did well but not as well.
在我的第二次 我做得很好 但不是那么好
And I got a 90.
我得了90分
And ironically, I'm not very good with math.
讽刺的是我数学不好
So I'd like to figure out what my average now is between those two tests.
所以我想知道这两次测试的平均值是多少
So let me go ahead now and in this list, type in the number
现在让我在这个列表中输入
100, comma, 90, thereby passing in a list of two values, two INTs, 190.
100 逗号 90 从而传入两个值的列表 两个INT 190
And outside of those are the parentheses because, of course,
在这些之外的是圆括号 因为 当然
this is now the argument I'm passing to the function called mean.
这就是我传递给mean函数的参数
And this function mean is in the module called statistics.
这个函数mean在statistics模块中
Well, it's not that interesting to just calculate the mean if I don't actually
如果我不计算平均值
see what it is.
看看是什么
So let me additionally pass the return value of that mean function
让我另外传递均值函数的返回值
to the print function as usual.
打印功能像往常一样
Let me now in my terminal window in VS Code, type
现在让我在VS Code的终端窗口中输入
in Python of average.py and hit Enter.
在average.py的Python中 然后按Enter键
And voila, as you might expect, my average is 95%.
瞧 正如你所料 我的平均分是95%
So the difference here is that I'm just using a different module that
所以这里的不同之处在于我只是使用了一个不同的模块
still comes with Python.
仍然与Python一起提供
But I need to import it instead of, for instance, the random module instead.
但我需要导入它 而不是导入随机模块
And this time, I know from the documentation
这一次 我从文件中得知
that there exists a function called mean.
存在一个叫做Mean的函数
Well, it turns out there's even more functionality that comes with Python
事实证明 在Python中还附带了更多的功能
and that comes with other modules in Python.
这是随其他Python模块一起提供的
And there's this feature generally known as command line arguments.
这个特性通常被称为命令行参数
This is a feature, not just of Python, but of languages
这不仅是Python的一个特性 也是语言的一个特性
more generally that allow you to provide input not when
更广泛地说 这允许您提供输入 而不是何时
prompted inside of a program as happens whenever we call the Python function
在程序内部提示 就像我们每次调用Python函数时发生的那样
input.
输入
But rather, there's this feature, command line arguments of programs,
相反 有这样一个功能 程序的命令行参数
that allows you to provide arguments that
这允许您提供以下参数
is input to the program of just when you're executing at the command line.
是程序的输入 当你在命令行执行的时候
So up until now, for instance, recall that we've generally
所以到目前为止 例如 回想一下 我们通常
run Python of something.py.
运行Something.py的Python
For instance, Python of hello.py.
例如 hello.py的Python
And I've never once really executed any words or phrases
我从来没有真正执行过任何单词或短语
after the name of the file, but I could.
以文件的名字命名 但我可以
In fact, when you're running programs in a command-like environment like we are,
事实上 当你像我们一样在类似命令的环境中运行程序时
you can provide any number of words or numbers or phrases after the command
您可以在命令后提供任意数量的单词、数字或短语
that you're typing.
你在打字
And all of those will somehow be passed in as inputs to the program itself.
所有这些都会以某种方式作为输入传递到程序本身
You don't have to prompt the user for one thing at a time
您不必一次提示用户做一件事
by manually calling that input function.
通过手动调用该输入函数
So what does this mean in real terms?
那么 这实际上意味着什么呢？
Well, let me go ahead back into VS Code here.
好了 让我们回到VS代码这里
And let me propose that we consider how we might leverage a certain module.
让我建议我们考虑如何利用某个模块
I'm going to go ahead and create a file called name.py.
我将继续创建一个名为name.py的文件
And I'd like to use a new module this time that's
这次我想用一个新模块 那就是
going to give me access to values that have been typed at the command line.
这将使我能够访问在命令行中键入的值
But what's this module going to be?
但是这个模块会是什么呢？
Well, this one's going to be called sys.
好的 这个将被命名为sys
And sys, short for system, contains a whole lot of functionality
sys是system的缩写 它包含了很多功能
that's specific to the system itself and the commands that you and I are typing.
这是特定于系统本身和你我正在输入的命令
The documentation for this module is at this URL here.
此模块的文档位于此URL
And it lists all of the various functions and variables and the like
它列出了所有的函数和变量
that come with that module.
模块附带的功能
But we're going to focus on something a little more specific,
但我们要关注一些更具体的东西
namely this thing here.
也就是这个东西
It turns out in the sys module in Python,
在Python的sys模块中
there is a variable that just magically exists for you called argv.
有一个变量 就像魔法一样存在 叫做argv
It stands for argument vector which is a fancy way of describing
它代表论点向量 这是一种描述
the list of all of the words that the human typed in at their prompt
人类在提示符下输入的所有单词的列表
before they hit Enter.
在他们按回车键之前
All of those are seemingly magically provided to you via Python
所有这些似乎都是通过Python神奇地提供给您的
in a variable called sys.argv.
一个名为sys.argv的变量
This variable is a list, which means that the first element is going
这个变量是一个列表 这意味着第一个元素将
to be the first word that you type.
你输入的第一个词
The second element is going to be the second word
第二个元素是第二个单词
that you typed in, so forth.
你输入的信息等等
And by way of this list, then, can you figure out
通过这个列表 你能找出
what words did the human actually type at the prompt and maybe use that
人类在提示符下实际输入了哪些单词
to influence the behavior of your own program?
来影响你自己程序的行为
So what does this mean now in real terms?
那么 这意味着什么呢？
Well, in this new tab called name.py, let me go ahead and import sys.
在这个名为name.py的新选项卡中 让我继续导入sys
Within that sys module is going to give me access to sys.argv, but how might
在sys模块中 将允许我访问sys.argv 但是如何才能
I want to use it?
我想用它？
Well, let's do this.
好吧 我们开始吧
Instead of writing a Hello World program that all of these times
而不是写一个Hello World程序
has just looked for the return value of input
刚刚查找了输入的返回值
to figure out what the user wants me to print,
来弄清楚用户想让我打印什么
let's go ahead and just expect the user to tell us
让我们继续 只是期待用户告诉我们
when they run the Python program itself, what their name is.
当他们运行Python程序本身时 他们的名字是什么
And suppose this time, I'd like to generate a whole bunch of name tags,
假设这一次 我想生成一大堆名字标签
initially just one.
最初只有一个
And in the US here, it's very common to wear a sticker on your lapel that
在美国这里 在翻领上贴一张贴纸是很常见的
says Hello, my name is David.
你好 我叫大卫
So I want to print out some text that resembles that.
所以我想打印出一些类似的文本
The idea being maybe I could enhance this program someday
我的想法是也许有一天我可以增强这个程序
to even send that text straight to the printer
直接把文本发送到打印机
and dynamically generate those name tags.
并动态生成这些名称标签
Well, let me go ahead now and do this.
好吧 让我继续做这个
Let me go ahead and print out as always, Hello.
让我像往常一样打印出来 你好
But I'll say a little something more this time
但这次我要多说点
to make things more interesting.
让事情变得更有趣
Hello, my name "is," quote, unquote.
你好 我叫“是” 引用 不引用
And then after that, I normally have been
在那之后 我通常
in the habit of calling input, storing the return value in a variable,
在调用input的习惯中 将返回值存储在变量中
and passing in the name of that variable here.
并在这里传入该变量的名称
But I'm going to instead jump right to this--
但我还是要直接跳到这个
sys.argvbracket1.
sys.argvbracket1.
And that's it.
就这样
I'm going to have a program here that says Hello, my name is followed
我会有一个程序说你好 我的名字被跟踪了
by whatever is in sys.argvbracket1.
sys.argvbracket1中的任何内容
And notice, this .argv again is a list.
注意 这个.argv也是一个列表
And recall from our discussion of loops and in turn list,
回顾我们对循环和循环列表的讨论
we use this square bracket notation to get at the various elements
我们用这个方括号来表示不同的元素
inside of a list.
在一个列表中
All right, let me go down now into my terminal window
好吧 让我现在下去到终端窗口
and run Python of name.py.
然后运行name.py的Python
But this time, rather than just hit Enter
但这一次
and wait for the program to prompt me for my name,
等待程序提示输入我的名字
let me proactively just tell this program what my name is
让我主动告诉这个程序我的名字
at the so-called command line.
所谓的命令行
Here we go.
开始吧
D-A-V-I-D separated with a space from the name of the file so that now when I
D-A-V-I-D与文件名之间用空格分隔 因此
execute Python, name.py David, I see on the screen, voila, Hello,
执行Python name.py大卫 我在屏幕上看到 瞧 你好
my name is David.
我叫大卫
So based on this demonstration alone, I think
所以仅基于这个演示 我认为
we can infer exactly what's going on in sys.argv
我们可以准确地推断出sys.argv中发生了什么
even though it sounds certainly at first glance, rather complicated here.
尽管乍看起来很复杂
Let's look up.
我们往上看
At sys.argv, I'm going to bracket1 here.
在sys.argv中 我在这里将括号1括起来
So clearly, sys.argvbracket1 is storing D-A-V-I-D. But it's one.
所以很明显 sys.argvbracket1存储的是D-A-V-I-D 但它是一个
In the past when we looked at loops, recall
回想一下 在过去我们研究循环时
that we said that they were zero index.
我们说它们是零指数
That is the first element is zero.
第一个元素是零
The next element is one.
下一个元素是1
This next element is two and so forth.
下一个元素是2 依此类推
And yet, here I am treating it as though my name
然而 在这里 我把它当作我的名字
is at the start of the list one.
位于列表一的开头
Well, let me ask this question, what is probably in sys.argv of 0?
那么 让我问这个问题 在sys.argv的0中可能是什么？
What is probably in sys.argv of 0--
0的sys.argv中可能有什么--
the very first element actually in that list?
列表中的第一个元素是什么？
AUDIENCE: Oh, yeah.
观众：哦 是的
I think it's like in C, the name of program.
我想它就像C中的程序名
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, it's indeed like in C. Another language
大卫·马兰：的确 这和C语言很像
is the name of the program.
是程序的名称
Well, if we consider what it was I typed,
如果我们考虑一下我打的是什么
I certainly typed Python because that's the name of my interpreter.
我当然输入了Python 因为这是我的解释器的名字
And we don't really need to know that because we're using Python itself.
我们真的不需要知道这一点 因为我们使用的是Python本身
But after that, I did type two things.
但在那之后 我打了两个字
I typed name.py as I've done so many times any time
我输入了name.py 就像我在任何时候做过很多次一样
I want Python to the interpreter program I've written.
我想要在我编写的解释器程序中使用Python
And it turns out by convention, what Python
事实证明 按照惯例
does is it stores in sys.argv the name of the file that you're executing
它是否将正在执行的文件的名称存储在sys.argv中
or interpreting followed by any number of other words that you type.
或口译 后跟您键入的任意数量的其他单词
So all this time, we could have been accessing
所以这段时间 我们可能一直在访问
the name of the program, which frankly, isn't all that interesting.
这个节目的名字 坦率地说 并不是那么有趣
But we can also now access words that are typed after that prompt as well.
但我们现在也可以访问在提示符后输入的单词
But of course, if I don't type anything in, what might happen here?
当然 如果我不输入任何内容 这里可能会发生什么？
This might be naive of me to assume that there's always
我可能太天真了 以为总会有
going to be something at location1 in sys.argv.
将会出现在sys.argv中的位置1处
Let me go ahead and try this.
让我来试试这个
Python, name.py.
Python.name.py
And I'm not giving you my name because at this point,
我不会给你我的名字 因为在这一点上
I might not even know that you want my name to be typed.
我甚至可能不知道你想把我的名字打出来
So let me hit Enter now.
现在让我按Enter键
And uh, oh, we see now an error.
呃 哦 我们现在看到一个错误
A so-called exception in Python, this one's a new one.
这是一个新的异常 这是在Python中的一个所谓的例外
This one's an index error that elaborates list index out of range.
这是一个索引错误 它详细说明了列表索引超出范围
And turns out this is actually one of the most common mistakes
事实证明 这实际上是最常见的错误之一
in programming, whether you're using a list in Python
在编程中 无论您使用的是Python中的列表
or arrays or vectors in other languages, is
或其他语言中的数组或向量 是
to try to access some element that does not exist.
尝试访问某些不存在的元素
You try to go too far to the left.
你试着向左走得太远
Or you try to go too far to the right in this object that
或者您尝试在此对象中向右走得太远
is just a list of some values.
只是一些值的列表
So of course, the mistake here is that I'm
所以当然 这里的错误是我是
assuming there's going to be something at location1
假设地点1会有什么东西
when really, it's location0.
实际上 它是位置0
That's the only one that has a value.
这是唯一有价值的东西
But fixing this is not going to amount to doing bracket0
但解决这个问题并不等同于做bracket0
because now if I go ahead and rerun this program with no other words
因为现在如果我继续运行这个程序 没有其他词
after name.py, it says Hello, my name is name.py, which is fine
在name.py之后 它会说你好 我的名字是name.py 这很好
if we're making a name tag for the program, but that's not,
如果我们要为这个项目做一个名牌 但那不是
of course, what my goal here is instead.
当然 我在这里的目标是
So if the fix is not just to change the one to a zero,
因此 如果解决办法不仅仅是将1改为0
how else might I handle this error?
我还能怎么处理这个错误呢？
This index error that happens if the user just doesn't remember to
如果用户不记得 就会出现这种索引错误
or doesn't know to type their actual name at the prompt.
或者不知道在提示符下输入他们的真实姓名
AUDIENCE: We could always put an exception into the program,
观众：我们总是可以在节目中加入一个例外
say, if there's nothing at location1, we just come out
比方说 如果地点1什么都没有 我们就出来
and say, OK, we haven't got parameter or something.
然后说 好的 我们没有参数什么的
But if there is, we continue along with the program.
但如果有的话 我们会继续这个项目
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
大卫·马兰：太好了
So if I might simplify, we can try to execute this line of code,
因此 如果我可以简化一下 我们可以尝试执行这行代码
except if there's an error, we'll deal with it in some other way.
除非出现错误 我们会以其他方式处理
Now, ideally-- and once I'm a strong enough programmer,
现在 理想的情况是 一旦我成为一个足够强大的程序员
I would have anticipated this and written the following code
我已经预料到了这一点 并编写了以下代码
from the get go.
从一开始
But when you're learning, it's certainly reasonable to see an error.
但当你在学习的时候 看到一个错误当然是合理的
Oh, I didn't realize I should detect that and then
哦 我没有意识到我应该发现这一点 然后
go back and improve your code.
返回并改进您的代码
But of course, if you read the documentation,
但当然 如果你阅读了文档
you ingrain some of the lessons learned from the past.
你牢牢记住了从过去学到的一些教训
You'll get into the habit of trying and checking for some of these exceptions
您将养成尝试并检查其中一些异常的习惯
yourself.
你自己
So let me solve this in one possible way as you've proposed here.
所以让我像你在这里提议的那样 用一种可能的方式来解决这个问题
Let's try to handle this exception as follows.
让我们尝试按如下方式处理此异常
Let me go ahead now.
现在让我继续说下去
And instead of just blindly calling this print line,
而不是盲目地给这条打印线打电话
let me try to print out Hello, my name is such and such,
让我试着打印出来你好 我的名字是某某
except if there is an issue, specifically an index error, then
除非出现问题 特别是索引错误 否则
what do I want to go ahead and do?
我想要做什么呢？
I'm going to say something like too few arguments.
我要说的是 论点太少了
I could be more explanatory than that.
我可以解释得更清楚
But for now, I'm just going to explain to the user
但现在 我只想向用户解释
that they gave me too few arguments, too few words at the prompt.
他们给我的论据太少 提示时的话太少
So now, it's still not going to work in quite the way I want.
所以现在 它仍然不会以我想要的方式工作
I'm still not going to be able to generate their name tag.
我还是不能生成他们的名牌
But at least, they're not going to see some cryptic error message
但至少 他们不会看到一些隐晦的错误消息
and think that they themselves broke the program.
并认为是他们自己破坏了程序
Let me go ahead now and run Python of name.py Enter and too few arguments.
现在让我继续运行名为e.py、Enter和参数太少的Python
OK, let me go ahead now and do Python of name.py and type in my name, David.
好的 现在让我继续执行名为.py的Python 然后输入我的名字David
And now we're back in business.
现在我们又重回正轨了
And I see that my name is on the screen too.
我看到我的名字也在屏幕上
But strictly speaking, I don't have to try to do this.
但严格地说 我不需要尝试这样做
I could actually be a little more defensive in writing this code.
在编写这段代码时 我实际上可以更具防御性
And maybe I could check whether or not the user has indeed
也许我可以检查用户是否真的
provided a name or multiple names at the prompt so as to give them
在提示符下提供一个或多个名称 以便提供这些名称
more refined error messages as well.
更精炼的错误消息也是如此
So how might I do this?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, me go and undo the exception handling I've added.
好了 我去撤销我添加的异常处理
And why don't I instead more modestly try to do this?
为什么我不更谦虚地尝试这样做呢？
Let me go ahead and introduce a conditional here.
让我继续在这里介绍一个有条件的
If the length of sys.argv is less than 2 or equivalently equal to just one
如果sys.argv的长度小于2或等价于仅等于1
value--
价值--
but I'll just stick with less than 2 for now,
但我现在只会坚持少于2个
then go ahead and print out two few arguments.
然后继续打印出两个论点
So I want ultimately two arguments.
所以我最终想要两个论点
I want the name of the program at location0.
我想知道0号位置的程序名称
And I want the name of the human at location1.
我要知道地点1的那个人的名字
So that's a total of two arguments.
这总共有两个论点
So if I have fewer than two arguments, let's
所以如果我的论点少于两个 让我们
tell the user with this print line, L if the length of sys.argv
用这行打印行告诉用户 L如果sys.argv的长度
is say greater than 2, like they typed in too many words at the prompt, well,
就是说大于2 就像他们在提示符下输入了太多的单词
let's tell them, print, quote, unquote, "too" many arguments.
让我们告诉他们 打印 引用 取消引用 太多的论点
Else if they did get it right, and they gave me exactly two arguments.
如果他们真的做对了 他们给了我两个论点
Else, let's go ahead and print what I actually care about.
否则 让我们继续打印我真正关心的内容
All right, let me go down to my terminal window
好的 让我去我的终端窗口
here and run Python of name.py and voila.
在这里 运行名为e.py的Python 看吧
Uh, oh, a completely different type of error.
啊 哦 一种完全不同类型的错误
This one a syntax error, which we've seen in the past.
这是一个语法错误 我们在过去已经看到过
Now, a syntax error recall is mea culpa, like, I messed up here.
现在 语法错误召回是我的错 就像 我把这里搞砸了
And I wrote invalid syntax.
我写了无效的语法
And so no amount of conditionals or exception handling's
所以没有太多的条件或异常处理
really going to catch this one.
真的要赶上这一次了
I need to go back and just get my program
我需要回去拿回我的程序
to work because it's not running at all.
工作 因为它根本没有运行
Well, let me go up here and see.
好的 让我上去看看
Line four is the issue.
第四行是问题所在
And indeed, it looks like I have an unterminated string here.
事实上 看起来我这里有一根未结束的字符串
I need to go ahead and now add this double quote.
我需要继续下去 现在添加这个双引号
So let me go ahead now.
所以现在让我继续下去
And with that red herring gone, let me rerun Python of name.py and hit Enter.
转移注意力后 让我重新运行名为e.py的Python 然后按Enter键
And now, we see too few arguments.
现在 我们看到的论据太少了
OK, maybe it wants my full name.
好吧 也许它想要我的全名
Let me go ahead now and run Python of name.py, David Malan,
现在让我继续运行名为.py的巨蟒 David Malan
typing in both words after the name of the file and hit Enter.
在文件名后面输入两个单词 然后按Enter键
And now, of course, it's too many arguments.
现在 当然 争论太多了
Fine.
很好
Now, I'll oblige and do Python of name.py and just David.
现在 我将执行名为e.py且仅名为David的Python
And there we have it.
现在我们就知道了
My name tag printed on the screen.
屏幕上印着我的名牌
So strictly speaking, we don't have to handle exceptions
所以严格地说 我们不需要处理异常
if we can be a little smarter about it and just check for the things
如果我们能更聪明一点 检查一下
that we're worried about, especially if we want
我们所担心的 特别是如果我们想
to give the user more refined advice.
为用户提供更精致的建议
We don't want to just tell them no, something went wrong
我们不想就这样告诉他们不 出了点问题
or we don't want to pass.
否则我们就不想通过
We want to tell them no, that's too few or no, that's too many.
我们想告诉他们不 要么太少 要么不 太多了
We have conditionals in our vocabulary already
我们的词汇中已经有条件句了
via which we can now express that.
我们现在可以通过它来表达这一点
Well, let me pause here and see if there's any questions now
好吧 让我在这里停一下 看看现在有没有什么问题
on how we handled the error before with the index error
关于我们之前如何处理索引错误的错误
or how now we're just proactively avoiding all index errors altogether
或者现在我们只是主动地完全避免了所有索引错误
by just checking first, is it too few?
先查一下 是不是太少了？
Is it too many?
是不是太多了？
Or is it exactly what we want?
或者这就是我们想要的？
AUDIENCE: Hi, yeah, thank you.
观众：嗨 是的 谢谢
So I was wondering, you touched upon using your full name.
所以我在想 你提到了你的全名
Is there a way going forwards that perhaps we
有没有什么办法可以让我们
have people that want their full names and want just their first name
有想要他们的全名而只想要他们的名字的人
that we separate that into, oh, this person has full name.
我们把它分成 哦 这个人有全名
This person has just the one name?
这个人只有一个名字？
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely, and allow me to propose we come back
大卫·马兰：当然 请允许我提议我们回来
to that support for multiple names.
对多个名称的支持
But indeed, we could do that.
但事实上 我们可以做到这一点
And I should note too, though, we can support
不过 我也应该指出 我们可以支持
full names right now if I do this.
如果我这么做的话现在就叫全名
Instead of typing in David space Malan, which is problematic because again,
而不是输入David space Malan 这是有问题的 因为再次
by definition of how are argv works, each word
根据argv是如何工作的定义 每个单词
ends up in a specific location in the list.
最终出现在列表中的特定位置
But if I add quotes, single quotes or double quotes at the command line,
但如果我在命令行添加引号、单引号或双引号
now, Python will view this as two total things.
现在 Python将把这看作是两件事
The name of the file and this full name.
文件的名称和此全名
And now, when I hit Enter, I don't see the quotes.
现在 当我按Enter键时 我看不到引号
The whole thing is passed in as my full name.
整件事都是作为我的全名传进来的
And if I want to adapt this further for multiple people,
如果我想让它进一步适应多个人
we'll be able to do that as well.
我们也能做到这一点
Other questions now on this version with if, elif, else, or on except before.
这个版本上的其他问题现在与If、Elif、Else或On有关 但之前没有
AUDIENCE: Python.
观众：巨蟒
I want to ask you, can we use multiple else's statement?
我想问你 我们可以使用多个其他人的陈述吗？
DAVID MALAN: Can you use multiple else's statements?
大卫·马兰：你能用多个其他人的陈述吗？
No, else is the last catchall statement that you can have.
不 Else是你可以拥有的最后一条笼统的声明
You can have multiple elif statements in the middle but not multiple elses.
中间可以有多个elif语句 但不能有多个else
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
DAVID MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的
All right, well, let's turn our attention back now to this code
好了 现在让我们把注意力转回到这个代码上
and see if we can't refine it a bit more by adding
看看我们能不能通过添加
in some additional functionality that we get with modules like the sys module.
在一些额外的功能中 我们可以使用像sys模块这样的模块
One of the things I don't love about this version of the code
我不喜欢这个版本的代码的原因之一是
even though arguably it is now correct is that the essence of my program,
尽管现在可以说它是正确的 但我的程序的本质
which is just to print out the name tag, is relegated to this else clause.
它只是打印出姓名标签 被归类到这个Else子句
And that's fine.
这很好
Logically, it's correct, but generally speaking,
从逻辑上讲 这是正确的 但总的来说
there is something nice about keeping all of your error
保留你所有的错误是有好处的
handling separate from the code that you really
与您真正需要的代码分开处理
care about having all of these ifs, elifs, perhaps at the top of your code
关心所有这些if、elif 可能位于代码的顶部
that are checking to make sure that all of the data's as expected.
他们正在检查以确保所有数据都是预期的
But then it would be nice if only for design sake
但如果只是为了设计的缘故 那就太好了
not to hide in this else statement the actual code that you care about.
不要在这个Else语句中隐藏您关心的实际代码
I would prefer, for instance, to do something logically like this.
例如 我更愿意做一些符合逻辑的事情
I could check for errors up top.
我可以在上面检查错误
And then down here, print the name tag.
然后在这里 打印名牌
It would be nice if those are distinct blocks of code all of which
如果这些代码是截然不同的代码块 那就太好了
are here left aligned.
在这里左对齐
But there's a problem with what I've just done here.
但我刚才所做的事情有个问题
Logically, what bug did I just introduce by getting rid of the else
从逻辑上讲 我刚刚通过去掉其他
and introducing line 10 on its own with no indentation
并单独引入第10行 没有缩进
outside of the conditional?
除了有条件的？
What bug have I just introduced?
我刚刚引入了什么错误？
What mistake to be clear?
需要澄清的错误是什么？
AUDIENCE: Name error.
观众：名字有误
DAVID MALAN: Ironically, it's a name error but not a name error exception.
David Malan：具有讽刺意味的是 这是一个名称错误 但不是一个名称错误例外
It's an error with my name, but I think you're frozen for me.
我的名字有误 但我想你为我定下了心
It's going to raise an exception because even
它将引发一个异常 因为即使
though I'm checking the length of sys.argv up top
虽然我在上面检查sys.argv的长度
and even though I'm checking it again for being greater than 2, not just less
即使我再次检查它是否大于2 而不是小于2
than 2, but greater, I'm still then blindly and incorrectly assuming
比2 但更大 我仍然盲目和错误地假设
it's now going to exist.
它现在将会存在
So just to be clear, if I run Python of name.py and I don't type any argument--
所以 为了清楚起见 如果我运行名为name.py的Python 并且我没有输入任何参数--
I've got too few--
我的钱太少了--
I think I'm going to see that I have too few,
我想我会发现我的钱太少了
but I'm also going to see that same exception.
但我也会看到同样的例外
At the very top of my terminal window's output,
在我的终端窗口输出的最顶端
there's my error message, too few arguments.
这是我的错误消息 参数太少了
But again, on line 10, I blindly proceed to still index into my list
但是 在第10行 我盲目地继续索引到我的列表
at location1 which does not exist.
在不存在的位置1
So it turns out there's a better way to handle errors like this, especially
所以事实证明 有一种更好的方法来处理这样的错误 特别是
if you're writing a program in Python that's just meant
如果你用Python写程序
to run briefly and then exit anyway.
短暂运行然后退出
But maybe we could start to exit prematurely if the program itself just
但如果程序本身
can't proceed.
无法继续
If the user has not given us the data we want,
如果用户没有提供我们想要的数据
perhaps, we should just exit the program earlier than we might otherwise.
也许我们应该提前退出程序
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续这样做
Let me go ahead and remove my comments so as to focus only on the code here.
让我继续下去 删除我的注释 以便只关注这里的代码
And let me propose that instead of just printing,
让我提议 除了印刷
quote, unquote, "too" few arguments, I'm going to use one other function that
引用 取消引用 “太”少的参数 我将使用另一个函数
comes with the sys module.
带有sys模块
I'm going to go ahead and call sys.exit.
我将继续并调用sys.exit
And as the name suggests, it's going to do exactly that.
正如它的名字所暗示的那样 它会做到这一点
With the system's help, it's going to exit my program then and there
在系统的帮助下 它会在那里退出我的程序
on line four.
四号线
Why is that OK?
为什么可以？
Well, if you gave me too few arguments, I
如果你给我的论据太少
have nothing more to say to you, the user.
我对用户没什么好说的了
I might as well exit a bit prematurely.
我可能会提前退出
And I can do this as well on line six.
我也可以在6号线上这样做
Let's go ahead and not just print that, but sys.exit, quote, unquote,
让我们继续 不只是打印出来 而是系统退出 引用 不引用
"too" many arguments.
“太多”的争论
Print out that message and just exit right there.
打印出这条信息 然后就在那里退出
Now, I can trust that by the time I get to line eight,
我可以相信当我到第八行的时候
every error condition has been checked for.
每一个错误条件都已经检查过了
And so it's safe for me to assume that there is in fact an item at location1
所以我可以假设在位置1确实有一个物品
in sys.argv.
在sys.argv中
So let me go ahead now and run this, Python
让我继续运行这个 Python
of name.py, Enter, too few arguments.
的name.py 输入 参数太少
But I'm back at my prompt.
但我又回到了我的提示
Nothing more has happened.
什么都没发生
Let me run it again.
我再检查一遍
Python of name.py David Malan with no quotes, Enter.
Python的name.py大卫马兰没有报价 输入
Too many arguments is now printed here.
现在这里打印了太多的参数
Finally, Python of name.py just David, Enter.
最后 名为e.py的Python只需David 回车
Hello, my name is David.
你好 我叫大卫
So we have then in sys two forms of functionality.
因此 我们在sys中有两种形式的功能
Now, we have access to this variable, sys.argv, this argument vector,
现在 我们可以访问这个变量sys.argv 这个自变量向量
that gives me all of the words that were typed at the prompt,
这给了我在提示符下输入的所有单词
including the program's own file name.
包括程序自己的文件名
And it turns out if we read further in the documentation,
事实证明 如果我们进一步阅读文档
there's an exit function that can take different types of input.
有一个出口函数 可以接受不同类型的输入
But if I pass out a string like this, it will indeed print that string for me
但如果我传递一个这样的字符串 它确实会为我打印该字符串
and then exit from my program then and there.
然后当场退出我的程序
Questions now on exiting from programs like this.
现在关于退出这样的节目的问题
To be clear, all of this time once Python gets to the bottom of your file,
需要明确的是 在这段时间里 一旦Python到达文件的底部
it's going to exit anyway.
它无论如何都会退出的
So I'm using sys.exit now just to make sure that I exit earlier than
所以我现在使用sys.exit 只是为了确保我早于
otherwise.
否则的话
AUDIENCE: My question is about the sys that arg--
观众：我的问题是关于那个系统--
argv.
阿格夫
So is that capable of accepting or taking multiple elements at once?
那么 它有能力同时接受或接受多种元素吗？
Let's say, for example, Python name.py, David Malan.
例如 让我们假设 Pythonname.py David Malan
I'm a male, 20 years old.
我是一名男性 20岁
And if let's say I only want to access your name, which is at the first index.
假设我只想访问你的名字 这是第一个索引
And then your age is, say, at the sixth index.
然后你的年龄 比方说 在第六位
Can I say sys.argv1 and another one for six to access what I just want?
我可以输入sys.argv1 然后再输入一个for Six来访问我想要的内容吗？
Is that both for sys.argv?
这都是给sys.argv的吗？
DAVID MALAN: Short answer-- yes, I think if I understand your question
David Malan：简短的回答--是的 我想如果我理解你的问题
correctly, whereby, you're proposing to have
正确地说 你是在提议
many words at the end of the command.
在命令的末尾有许多单词
And you want to access those individual words.
你想要访问这些单独的单词
Absolutely.
绝对一点儿没错
At some point, it gets a little fragile, I would say,
在某种程度上 它会变得有点脆弱 我会说
if you're typing so many words at the prompt that the order really matters.
如果您在提示符下输入的单词太多 那么顺序真的很重要
And so it turns out there's a lot of programs.
所以事实证明 有很多项目
And there's functionality in Python that can
而且 在Python中有一些功能可以
allow you to provide those values, like name or age
允许您提供这些值 如姓名或年龄
or any number of other fields in any order
或以任意顺序排列的任意数量的其他字段
you want, but a pass in a bit more information textually
您想要的 但需要以文本形式传入更多信息
that tells the program how you want to use it.
这会告诉程序您想要如何使用它
So in short, what you're describing is possible.
所以简而言之 你所描述的一切都是可能的
And let me do a small incarnation of it as follows.
让我做一个小化身 如下所示
Let me propose that we go back to my code here.
让我建议我们在这里回到我的代码
And let's propose that we actually now want
让我们假设我们现在实际上想要
to support multiple values at the prompt.
在提示符下支持多个值
So there's going to be no such thing as too many arguments.
所以不会有太多的争论
Suppose that I want to generate name tags not just for David, but for David,
假设我不仅要为David生成姓名标签 而且还要为David生成姓名标签
for Carter, for Rongshin, for others in the group who
为了卡特 为了荣申 为了集团中的其他人
all want their name tags as well.
所有人都想要自己的名牌
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
所以我要继续做这件事
I'm going to get rid of my elif condition
我要摆脱我的埃利夫病症
because I don't want to limit the maximum number of words
因为我不想限制最大字数
that are typed at the prompt anymore.
它们不再是在提示符下键入的
I instead want to iterate over every name at the prompt.
相反 我想在提示符下遍历每个名字
So I'm going to say this.
所以我要说的是
For arginsys.argv, go ahead and print out this time, arg.
对于arginsys.argv 继续并打印出来 arg
So what am I doing here?
那我在这里做什么？
Well, even though the syntax is a little different,
嗯 尽管语法有一点不同
the idea's the same as before when we've had loop.
这个想法和以前我们有循环的时候是一样的
I'm using a for loop to iterate over a list.
我正在使用for循环来迭代列表
The list in question here is sys.argv.
这里有问题的列表是sys.argv
Arg is a variable that I'm creating on the fly.
Arg是我动态创建的变量
The for loop is going to make sure that the first time through this loop, arg
For循环将确保第一次通过此循环时 arg
is set to the first word on the command line.
设置为命令行上的第一个单词
The second time through the loop, Python's
在第二次循环中 Python的
going to make sure that arg is now set to the second thing on the command line
确保Arg现在设置为命令行上的第二项内容
and so forth.
以此类推
That's just how a for loop works.
这就是for循环的工作方式
It updates the variable for us.
它会为我们更新变量
I don't have to call it arg.
我不一定要叫它Arg
I could call it name so long as I change it to name in both places.
我可以叫它的名字 只要我在两个地方都把它改成名字
But arg is reasonable if I'm iterating over arguments more generally.
但是 如果我迭代更一般的参数 Arg是合理的
If I now run this program, though, unfortunately, there's
不幸的是 如果我现在运行这个程序
a little bit of a bug.
有一点小毛病
Even if I type in David and Carter and Rongshin,
即使我输入大卫、卡特和荣申
I'm not going to get just three name tags.
我不会只拿到三个名牌的
In your mind, does anyone see the bug I'm about to trip over?
在你的脑海里 有没有人看到我即将被绊倒的虫子？
It's not a huge deal if I've got enough name tags to go around.
如果我有足够的名牌 这不是一个巨大的交易
But I'm going to be wasting one because this
但我会浪费一个因为
is going to print not three, but four name tags, whereby, the first contains
将打印不是三个 而是四个姓名标签 其中 第一个包含
the name of the program itself.
程序本身的名称
Maybe not a big deal.
也许没什么大不了的
Maybe that's the sticker we don't bother handing out, but it's wasteful.
也许这是我们懒得分发的贴纸 但这是浪费
And it does look wrong.
看上去确实不对
So how could we get access to not all four elements of argv
那么我们怎样才能访问argv的四个元素呢
but just a slice of argv?
但只是一片argv吗
And this is actually a technical term in Python and some other languages.
这实际上是Python和其他一些语言中的一个技术术语
To take a slice of a list means to take a subset of it
取列表的一部分意味着取列表的子集
maybe from the beginning, maybe the middle, maybe the end.
也许是从头开始 也许是中间 也许是结尾
But a slice is a subset of a data structure like a list.
但切片是数据结构（如列表）的子集
Well, how do I actually do this in code?
那么 我实际上是如何用代码来实现的呢？
Well, in Python, it's actually very easy to take a slice
在Python中
of a list that is a subset thereof.
一个列表是它的子集
You can simply do this.
你可以简单地这样做
At the end of the list name, sys.argv in this case, you can use square brackets.
在列表名称（本例中为sys.argv）的末尾 可以使用方括号
And then in those square brackets, you can
然后在那些方括号里 你可以
specify the start and the end of the list that you want to retain.
指定要保留的列表的开始和结束
I want to start at element1, not zero.
我想从元素1开始 而不是零
I want to start at element1, and I want to just go to the end.
我想从element1开始 然后一直到最后
So I'm actually going to omit a second number altogether.
所以我打算省略掉第二个数字
It's not necessary to have a second number.
没有必要有第二个数字
But I do need that colon because this is going to give me a slice of the list.
但我需要那个冒号因为它会给我列表的一部分
It's going to give me a slice of the list that
它会给我列表中的一部分
starts at location1, not zero.
从位置1开始 而不是零
And the colon and then a blank just means
冒号和空格的意思是
it's going to give me everything else.
它会给我其他的一切
So this is in equivalently going to slice off the first element of the list
所以这是等价的 切掉列表的第一个元素
and give me a new list that contains just those three human names, not
给我一个新的名单 只包含这三个人的名字 而不是
the name of the file itself.
文件本身的名称
Let me try running this again.
让我再试一次
I'm going to run Python of name.py, David Carter Rongshin.
我要运行name.py的Python David Carter Rongshin
This time hopefully, I'm going to get three and only three name tags,
希望这次 我能拿到三个而且只有三个名牌
hitting Enter.
按回车键
And indeed, I've done now just this.
事实上 我现在已经做到了这一点
So again, using some relatively simple syntax in Python,
因此 同样 使用一些相对简单的Python语法
we can use square brackets not just to go to specific elements like bracket0
我们可以使用方括号 而不仅仅是转到特定的元素 如bracket0
or bracket1.
或括号1
We can also get subsets of the list, slices of the list
我们还可以获得列表的子集、列表的片段
by doing bracket something colon something where each of those
通过使用方括号来冒号某物 其中每一个
some things is a number, the beginning or the end,
有些东西是一个数字 无论是开始还是结束
and they're optional depending on whether you
它们是可选的 取决于您是否
want all of them or just some.
全部都要 或者只想要一些
Any questions now on this version, which adds the loop and these slices
现在有任何关于这个版本的问题吗 它添加了循环和这些切片
with that new syntax?
使用这种新的语法？
AUDIENCE: Can we slice starting from the end of the argument-- argument vector?
听众：我们能从论点的结尾--论点向量开始切分吗？
DAVID MALAN: You can.
大卫·马兰：你可以的
You can slice something from the end of the argument vector.
你可以从自变量向量的末尾切分一些东西
And this might blow one's mind a little bit.
这可能会让人有点震惊
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续做这件事
Let's see.
让我们看看
Let me go ahead and do negative one at the end.
让我继续 在最后做一个负的
Using a negative number here and running the same command,
在这里使用负数并运行相同的命令
we've just uninvited Rongshin from receiving a name tag here.
我们刚刚取消了荣申在这里收到的名牌
So if you use a negative number, it has the effect
所以如果你使用负数 它会产生这样的效果
of counting in the other direction from the end of the list.
从列表的末尾开始向另一个方向计数
A good question there.
这是个好问题
Other questions now on slices, on looping over sys.argv?
其他问题现在在切片上 关于在sys.argv上循环？
AUDIENCE: Hi, so I remember very early on when
观众：嗨 我记得很早的时候
we were talking about only having two decimal places in float value.
我们讨论的浮点值只有两位小数
Is that in the same vein, like, because we use the code on 0.2F?
这是不是也是一样的 因为我们在0.2F上使用代码？
Is that the same thing then?
那是一回事吗？
Why would the F be included then in the 0.2F as opposed to here when you just
为什么F会包括在0.2F中 而不是这里 当你只是
have the numbers?
有数字吗？
DAVID MALAN: A really good question.
大卫·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
And it's just the short answer's that context matters.
简而言之 背景很重要
So there's only so many keys on our keyboard.
所以我们的键盘上只有这么多键
And so we sometimes use the same symbols for different things.
所以我们有时会用相同的符号来表示不同的东西
So what you're alluding to is the format code
所以你所指的是格式码
in an F string for actually formatting a number using a colon, using a period,
在用于实际使用冒号、使用句点来格式化数字的F字符串中
using a number, using the letter F and so forth.
使用数字、使用字母F等等
And that is very specific to the F string feature of Python.
这是Python的F字符串特性所特有的
This case has nothing to do with any of that syntax per se.
这种情况与语法本身无关
This is just using a colon in a different context
这只是在不同的上下文中使用冒号
to solve this problem to implement a slice.
来解决这个问题 实现一个切片
The authors of Python could have chosen another symbol.
Python的作者可以选择另一个符号
But honestly looking down at my keyboard here,
但老实说 看着我的键盘
we don't have that many to choose from that are easy to type.
我们没有那么多容易打字的选择
So sometimes they have different meanings.
有时候它们有不同的含义
A good question as well.
也是个好问题
Allow me to propose now, that we take things further
现在请允许我提议 我们进一步
and move away from using only those modules, those libraries that Python
不再只使用那些模块 那些Python
comes with to talk about more generally packages that exist.
来谈论更普遍的软件包
One of the reasons that Python is so popular and powerful these days
Python如今如此流行和强大的原因之一是
is that there's a lot of third-party libraries
有很多第三方库
out there as well, otherwise known as packages.
也就是所谓的包裹
Strictly speaking, Python itself has a term of art
严格地说 Python本身有一个艺术术语
called a package, which is a module essentially
称为包 它本质上是一个模块
that's implemented in a folder, not just a file but a folder.
在一个文件夹中实现 不仅仅是一个文件 而是一个文件夹
But more generally, a package is a third-party library that you,
但更一般地说 包是一个第三方库
that I can install on our own Mac or PC or our cloud server
我可以安装在我们自己的Mac或PC或云服务器上
and gain access to even more functionality
并获得更多功能
that other people have implemented for us.
其他人为我们实现的
Now, one of the locations you can get all of these packages
现在 你可以得到所有这些包裹的地点之一
is called the PYTI website, the Python Package Index which lives at this URL
称为PYTI网站 Python包索引位于此URL
here.
这里.
And this is a website that is searchable via the command line,
这是一个可以通过命令行搜索的网站
as well as via the web, that allows you to download and install
也可以通过网络下载和安装
all sorts of packages.
各种各样的包裹
Even CS50 has some of its own packages in services like these.
即使是CS50也有一些自己的服务包
Now, there's a fun one out there that's a throwback to a command that's
现在 有一个有趣的 这是一个倒退到一个命令
been around for years in command line environments called cowsay.
在命令行环境中已经存在了很多年 叫做cowsay
Cowsay is a package in Python that allows you to have a cow say something
Cowsay是Python中的一个包 它允许你让一头牛说些什么
on your screen.
在你的屏幕上
If curious to read up on it, its own documentation
如果你有兴趣阅读它 它自己的文档
is on pi.py.org specifically at this URL here.
在pi.py.org上 特别是这里的这个URL
But how do you actually get the package into your system?
但是 您实际上是如何将该包输入您的系统的呢？
Well, technically, you could figure out how to download the file
从技术上讲 你可以想办法下载这个文件
and maybe unzip it and put it into the right location on your Mac or PC.
或许还可以将其解压 放到Mac或PC上的正确位置
But nowadays, a lot of languages, Python among them,
但如今 许多语言 其中包括Python
has what's called its own package manager.
有所谓的自己的包管理器
This one here called pip which is just one.
这里的这个叫pip 它只是一个
So pip is a program that generally comes with Python itself, nowadays,
所以PIP是一个程序 通常是随Python本身一起提供的
that allows you to install packages onto your own Macs or PCs
允许您在自己的Mac或PC上安装程序包
or cloud environment by just running a command.
或云环境 只需运行一条命令
And then voila, you have access to a whole new library in Python
然后 瞧 您可以访问一个全新的Python库
that didn't come with Python itself.
这并不是随Python本身一起提供的
But now it's available on your system for you.
但现在它可以在您的系统上为您提供
Let's go back to VS Code here.
让我们回到这里的VS代码
And in my terminal window, I'm going to go ahead and type pip install cowsay.
在我的终端窗口中 我将继续输入pip installcosay
Now, what's going on here?
现在 这是怎么回事？
Pip is the command, the package manager.
Pip是命令 是包管理器
And I want to install what package?
我想安装什么程序包？
The package called cowsay.
这个套餐叫做牛仔套餐
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter here.
我将继续并在这里按Enter键
And after a little bit of output, it has successfully installed cowsay.
经过一点点的产出 它已经成功地安装了COROWAY
Now, what does that mean?
那么 这意味着什么呢？
That means I can now go about importing this into my own code.
这意味着我现在可以着手将其导入到我自己的代码中
Well, let's go ahead and see what this means.
好吧 让我们继续下去 看看这意味着什么
So let me go ahead and create a new file with code called say.py
因此 让我们继续创建一个名为say.py的新文件
because I want something to be said on the screen.
因为我想在屏幕上说点什么
And in my new tab here, I'm going to go ahead and import cowsay,
在我的新选项卡中 我将继续导入牛肝菌
which presumably is now installed.
现在大概已经安装好了
I'm now going to import sys as well because I'd
我现在也要导入系统 因为我
like to use some command line arguments in this program
我想在此程序中使用一些命令行参数
just so that I can run it quickly.
这样我就能快点跑了
And without using the input function, I can get the user's name
而且不使用输入函数 我就可以获得用户名
immediately from the prompt.
立即从提示符开始
And let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续做这件事
I'm going to do a bit of error checking proactively this time.
这一次 我将主动执行一些错误检查
And rather than use less than or greater than, I'm
而不是使用小于或大于 我是
this time going to say if the length of sys.argv does equal 2.
这一次将说明sys.argv的长度是否等于2
So if the human is provided just the name
所以如果这个人只是被提供了名字
of the program and their own first name, we're good to go.
以及他们自己的名字 我们就可以开始了
I'm going to do the following.
我将执行以下操作
I'm going to call a function called COW in the package called cowsay.
我将在包中调用一个名为cow的函数 该函数名为cowsay
And I'm going to pass in a string, hello, comma.
我将传入一个字符串 你好 逗号
And then as in the past, I'm going to pass in just one string
然后像过去一样 我将只传递一个字符串
because according to its documentation, it's not like print.
因为根据它的文件 它不像印刷品
I can't pass in comma this, comma that.
我不能用逗号这个 逗号那个
I can only pass in one string.
我只能传入一个字符串
So I'm going to concatenate it the contents of sys.argv, bracket1.
所以我将把它与sys.argv bracket1的内容连接起来
So long as then I type in my name David after the name of this program,
只要我在这个程序的名字后面输入我的名字David
it should end up in sys.argv1 in which case, this line five of code
它应该以sys.argv1结束 在这种情况下 代码的第5行
should concatenate hello with my name with a space in between.
应该把Hello和我的名字连接起来 中间加一个空格
And apparently, a cow is going to say it.
很明显 一头牛会这么说
So let's see what happens here.
所以让我们看看这里会发生什么
Let me go ahead and clear my screen and increase
让我继续清除我的屏幕并增加
the size of my terminal window.
我的终端窗口的大小
Let me go ahead and run Python of say.py and type my name David and Enter.
让我继续运行say.py的Python 然后输入我的名字David并回车
There is the program called cowsay.
有一个节目叫“牛仔”
It literally has a cow say something on the screen.
它确实让一头牛在屏幕上说了些什么
And this is a throwback to a program from yesteryear
这是对过去一个节目的倒退
that tended to come with a lot of systems.
这往往伴随着许多系统
This is otherwise known as ASCII art.
这也被称为ASCII ART
It's a textual way using just keys on your keyboard
这是一种只使用键盘上的按键的文本方式
to print pictures of sorts on the screen.
在屏幕上打印各种图片
Now, we can really go down the rabbit hole here.
现在 我们真的可以走进兔子洞了
And there's questionable academic value of doing so.
这样做的学术价值值得怀疑
So I'll do so just once.
所以我只会这么做一次
Turns out the cowsay package comes with other functions as well.
原来 COWSAY套餐还附带了其他功能
One of those functions, for instance, is T-Rex.
例如 霸王龙就是其中的一个功能
And if I now increase the size of my terminal window,
如果我现在增加终端窗口的大小
we'll perhaps see where we're going with this.
我们可能会看到我们将如何处理这件事
Let me now run again, Python of say.py.
现在让我再运行一次 Say.py的Python
This time, let me not provide my name just to see if it's broken.
这一次 让我不提供我的名字只是为了看看它是不是坏了
It's still OK because we have that if condition
还是可以的 因为我们有如果的条件
if the length of sys.argv equals equals 2 and only if it equals equals 2,
如果sys.argv的长度等于等于2并且仅当它等于等于2时
do we do anything.
我们做任何事情
That's why we're not seeing anything here.
所以我们什么都没看到
Let me go ahead and cooperate now, say.py space David.
让我继续合作吧 大卫 say.py
And it's no longer a cow.
它不再是一头牛了
But if I zoom out on my screen, a T-Rex.
但如果我把屏幕拉远一只霸王龙
Why?
为什么要这样？
Just because these are the things you can do once you know how to program.
只是因为这些是你一旦知道如何编程就可以做的事情
You can even package them up and make them freely available to others
你甚至可以把它们打包起来 让其他人免费使用
as open source software.
开源软件
For us, it's demonstrative of a feature more generally here
对我们来说 这是一个更普遍的特征的展示
namely being able to install these third-party packages and how
即能够安装这些第三方软件包
you might do so in Python.
你可以在Python中这样做
Now, I'll leave this up on the screen for a moment
现在 我把这个留在屏幕上一会儿
and see if there's any questions about cows
看看有没有关于奶牛的问题
or Tyrannosaurus rex's or packages more generally.
或者霸王龙的或者更普遍的包裹
I'm really qualified to speak to just one of those.
我真的有资格和他们中的一个说话
AUDIENCE: Hi, I've got two questions it's a bit earlier than what's
观众：嗨 我有两个问题
supposed to be.
应该是的
So the first question is the packages that you're
所以第一个问题是
calling to use in the program, are they the same
在程序中调用 它们是否相同
as, let's say, something Java the same as calling a class, a Java file
比如说 Java的东西 就像调用类 Java文件一样
in order to use its functions?
为了使用它的功能？
And my second question is, what's the actual purpose of using command line
我的第二个问题是 使用命令行的实际目的是什么
arguments as you used because is not really the best way to, as you say,
因为这不是最好的方法 就像你说的
be user friendly where as in let's say the person who's
对用户友好 比如说
using the program doesn't know what they want--
使用这个程序的人不知道他们想要什么--
what the program's asking them?
程序在问他们什么
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
大卫·马兰：问得好
The first question about the comparison with Java, Python packages
第一个关于与Java、Python包比较的问题
are similar to Java packages where you have something.something.something
类似于Java包 你有一些东西
at the top of your program that gives you
在你的程序的顶部
access to a class or something else.
访问类或其他东西
Python itself supports classes.
Python本身支持类
More on those down the road.
更多关于那些在路上
And you can do very similar things in Python as you can do with Java.
你可以在Python中做与Java非常相似的事情
But the analog really is Python packages to Java packages here.
但这里的类比实际上是Python包到Java包
As for command line arguments, you ask a good question.
至于命令行参数 您提出了一个很好的问题
Why do we use them, especially if they are literally user friendly?
我们为什么要使用它们 特别是如果它们确实是用户友好的呢？
They're a little less user friendly to people
他们对人们的使用不太友好
who aren't in this Zoom to be honest.
老实说 他们不在这个变速箱里
You and I as we learn more and more about programming
你和我随着我们对编程的了解越来越多
and more about command line arguments, I daresay
以及更多关于命令行参数的信息 我敢说
we'll become more comfortable with and tend
我们会变得更适应和照顾
to prefer the ability to customize commands using these command line
更喜欢使用这些命令行自定义命令的功能
arguments.
争论
Why?
为什么？
Productivity.
生产力
It tends to make you faster because you get
它往往会让你更快 因为你得到了
into the habit of knowing exactly how you
养成了一种习惯 即确切地知道你是如何
can configure your software without having to manually answer questions.
无需手动回答问题即可配置您的软件
And case in point.
这就是一个很好的例子
All of this time have we been running Python of something.py.
在这段时间里 我们一直在运行某个.py版本的Python
You could imagine not doing that.
你可以想象不会这样做
You can imagine typing only Python, hitting Enter.
您可以想象只输入Python 然后按Enter键
And then you're prompted for the name of the file you want to run.
然后系统会提示您输入要运行的文件的名称
So you type in something.py, and then it runs.
所以你输入一些东西.py 然后它就会运行
Not a big deal, but I would argue that over time, you're
没什么大不了的 但我认为随着时间的推移 你是
going to get a little tired of that TDM.
我会对TDM感到有点厌倦的
And you would much prefer to just automate
你会更喜欢自动操作
the command again and again and again, especially with little conveniences
一次又一次的命令 尤其是一些小的方便
like being able to hit up and down in your keyboard history
比如能够在你的键盘历史记录中上下敲击
so as to rerun those same command.
以便重新运行相同命令
Automation is big too if you emerge from a class like this
如果你从这样的课堂上走出来 自动化也很重要
and start using Python to automate processes
并开始使用Python自动化流程
at work or for personal projects or the like,
在工作或个人项目等方面
the ability to specify all of your inputs on the one line
能够在一行中指定所有输入
just means you can get work done more quickly.
只是意味着你可以更快地完成工作
So hands down, absolutely.
所以毫不费力 绝对是
Using command line arguments is a more arcane feature of systems
使用命令行参数是系统的一项更神秘的功能
that most of us are no longer as familiar with because
我们中的大多数人不再那么熟悉 因为
of Windows and Mac OS and other operating systems that
Windows和Mac OS以及其他操作系统的
have buttons and GUIs and menus.
有按钮、图形用户界面和菜单
But the more comfortable you get with programming,
但你对编程的适应程度越高
I daresay the more you will tend to prefer these capabilities because they
我敢说 您越倾向于使用这些功能 因为它们
allow you to do things more quickly.
让你做事更快
With that said, allow me to propose that we take a turn toward, yet,
话虽如此 请允许我提议我们转向 然而
another package that's particularly popular and just as easy
另一个特别受欢迎的软件包
to install all toward an end of using APIs.
来安装所有的API
Now, APIs are not something that's Python-specific.
API并不是Python特有的
More generally, an API is an application programming interface.
更一般地 API是应用程序编程接口
And it can refer to Python files and functions.
它可以引用Python文件和函数
But often, APIs really refer to third-party services
但通常 API实际上指的是第三方服务
that you and I can write code that talk to.
你和我可以写代码和它对话
Many APIs, but not all, live on the internet these days
许多API 但不是全部 这些天生活在互联网上
so that so long as you have a browser or so long
所以只要你有一个浏览器
as you have some experience with Python programming or programming
如果你有一些Python编程或编程的经验
in any language, you can write code that in effect pretends to be a browser,
在任何语言中 您都可以编写实际上假装是浏览器的代码
connects to that third-party API on a server,
连接到服务器上的第三方API
and download some data that you can then incorporate into your own program.
然后下载一些数据 你可以把它们合并到你自己的程序中
Now, how do you do this?
现在 你是怎么做到的？
Well, Python has a very popular package that you
Python有一个非常流行的包
can install via pip called requests.
可以通过pip安装所谓的请求
The requests library allows you to make web request,
requests库允许您发出web请求
internet request using Python code essentially
Internet请求基本上使用Python代码
as though you were a browser yourself.
就像你自己是一个浏览器
You can automate, therefore, the retrieval of URLs
因此 您可以自动检索URL
that start with HTTP or HTTPS.
以HTTP或HTTPS开头
The documentation for this library is that a URL like this,
这个库的文档是这样的URL
but it too can be installed at the command line.
但它也可以在命令行中安装
And even though it's third party, it's one
即使是第三方
of the most popular and commonly used packages out there in Python.
Python中最流行和最常用的包
And this too is one of the reasons again that Python is so popular.
这也是Python如此受欢迎的原因之一
There's just so many solutions to problems
解决问题的方法太多了
that you and I have or are invariably going to have
你和我已经或将要
when we write projects of our own.
when we write写projects项目of our own拥有.
There's just a really vibrant ecosystem, a really vibrant community
这是一个充满活力的生态系统 一个充满活力的社区
of open source software that's that easy for us to install.
开源软件 对我们来说很容易安装
Let me go back to my terminal window now and run
让我回到我的终端窗口现在运行
pip install requests in order to install this package on my own system.
PIP安装请求 以便在我自己的系统上安装此程序包
And after some lines of output, I'll see that it's successfully installed.
在几行输出之后 我将看到它已成功安装
Now, let's go ahead and create a new file here.
现在 让我们继续在这里创建一个新文件
For instance, itunes.py.
例如 itunes.py
It turns out that Apple has its own API for their iTunes service.
事实证明 苹果有自己的iTunes服务API
The software that provides you with the ability
为您提供功能的软件
to download and search for music and songs and other information as well.
下载和搜索音乐和歌曲以及其他信息
And it turns out that-- let me go back over to my computer
事实证明--让我回到我的电脑上
here and open up a browser like Chrome.
在这里打开一个类似Chrome的浏览器
And let me go ahead and visit this URL here,
让我继续访问这个URL
https://itunes.apple.com/ search?entity=song&amp;limit=1&amp;term=weezer.
Https://itunes.apple.com/search?entity=song&amp；limit=1&amp；term=weezer.
Search?entity=song&amp; limit=1&amp;term=weezer.
搜索？Entity=Song&amp；Limit=1&amp；Term=Weezer
Now, I constructed this URL manually by reading
现在 我通过阅读以下内容手动构建了这个URL
the documentation for Apple's API--
苹果API的文档--
application programming interface for iTune.
ITune的应用程序编程接口
And what they told me is that if I want to search for information about songs
他们告诉我 如果我想搜索关于歌曲的信息
in their database, I should specify entity
在他们数据库中 我应该指定实体
equals song so that songs and not albums or artists or something like that.
等于歌曲 所以歌曲而不是专辑或艺术家或类似的东西
If I just want to get back information on one song,
如果我只想拿回一首歌的信息
I'm going to provide limit equals 1.
我将提供等于1的限制
And if the band I want to search for, the artist is Weezer,
如果我要找的乐队 艺术家是Weezer
I should specify term equals Weezer.
我应该指定术语等于Weezer
So with this, if I go ahead and hit Enter and visit this URL,
因此 如果我继续按Enter键并访问此URL
I actually end up with a text file in my Downloads folder on my Mac.
实际上 我在Mac上的下载文件夹中看到了一个文本文件
If I go ahead and open that text file that my browser just downloaded,
如果我继续打开浏览器刚刚下载文本文件
we'll see all of this text here, which at first glance
我们将在这里看到所有这些文本 乍一看
might look a bit cryptic, but it actually follows a pattern.
可能看起来有点神秘 但它实际上遵循了一个模式
Notice this curly brace at the start and notice this
请注意开头的花括号 并注意以下内容
closed curly brace at the end.
末尾有一个闭合的花括号
Notice this open square bracket here and notice this closed square bracket here.
注意这里的左方括号和这里的闭方括号
And in between those pieces of syntax are
在这些语法之间有
a whole bunch of strings and values.
一大堆字符串和值
In fact, a whole bunch of key value pairs.
事实上 这是一大堆键值对
What we're looking at here is a standard text format known as JSON--
我们现在看到的是一种标准的文本格式 叫做JSON
JavaScript Object Notation, which yes, is technically related to yet,
JavaScript对象表示法 是的 在技术上是相关的
another programming language called JavaScript.
另一种编程语言叫做JavaScript
But JSON itself is typically used nowadays
但JSON本身现在通常被用于
as a language agnostic format for exchanging data between computers.
作为在计算机之间交换数据的语言无关格式
By language agnostic, I mean you don't have to use JavaScript.
所谓语言无关 我的意思是你不必使用JavaScript
You can use Python or any other language to read JSON or write it as well.
您可以使用Python或任何其他语言来读取或编写JSON
And it's a completely text-based format, which
它是一种完全基于文本的格式
means that if I visit that URL with my browser, what gets downloaded
意味着如果我用浏览器访问该URL
is just a bunch of text.
只是一堆文字
But that text is formatted in a standard way using curly braces
但该文本是用花括号以标准方式格式化的
and square bracket using quotes and some colons that ultimately contains
并使用引号和一些冒号进行方括号 最终包含
all of the information in Apple's database on Weezer's song, at least,
至少苹果数据库中关于Weezer歌曲的所有信息
the first one because I limited it to one in their database.
第一个是因为我把它限制在他们数据库里的一个
And that's an API, an application programming interface.
这是一个API 一个应用程序编程接口
A mechanism whereby I can access data on someone else's server
一种机制 使我可以访问其他人的服务器上的数据
and somehow integrate it into my own program.
并以某种方式将其整合到我自己的程序中
Now, of course, my browser, Chrome, is not something I wrote.
当然 我的浏览器Chrome不是我写的
I should actually write some Python code that perhaps pretends
我应该写一些Python代码
to be a browser to grab this same data.
成为一个浏览器来获取同样的数据
So let's do that.
我们就这么做吧
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我们回到VS Code
And let me write a program with code, itunes.py.
让我用代码写一个程序 itunes.py
And we're going to write some code via which I can then use the iTunes API
我们将编写一些代码 通过这些代码 我可以使用iTunes API
and in turn, Python to get information about any band that I might want.
反过来 Python可以获取我想要的任何乐队的信息
I'm going to go here and import first the requests
我将在这里首先导入请求
library, which I installed earlier in order to make those HTTP requests.
库 我之前安装它是为了发出那些HTTP请求
I'm going to go ahead and import the sys library via which I'll have the ability
我将继续导入sys库 通过它
to use command line arguments like specification of the band
使用命令行参数 如波段的规格
that I want to search for if not Weezer.
如果不是威瑟的话我也要找
And then down here, I'm going to go ahead and insert some error checking
然后在这里 我将继续插入一些错误检查
to say if the length of sys.argv does not equal to--
如果sys.argv的长度不等于--
so if the user does not provide me with the name of the file
因此 如果用户不向我提供文件名
they want to run and the name of a band, and that's it, you know what.
他们想要竞选和一个乐队的名字 就这样 你知道吗
Let's just go ahead and exit for now.
让我们先走一步 然后暂时离开
I could provide a more explanatory message.
我可以提供一个更具解释性的信息
But for now, I'm going to keep things simple
但现在 我会让事情变得简单
and just exit the program prematurely so that I can trust hereafter
提前退出程序 这样我以后就可以信任了
that sys.argv has what I want.
那个sys.argv有我想要的东西
And now, I have the opportunity to use the requests library to write
现在 我有机会使用请求库编写
some Python code that effectively is pretending
一些有效地伪装的Python代码
to be a web browser so as to connect to that same HTTPS
成为Web浏览器 以便连接到相同的HTTPS
URL on Apple's own server.
苹果自己的服务器上的URL
So now that I've guaranteed that the user has typed in
现在我已经保证用户已经输入了
not just the name of the file, but also the name of a band at the prompt
提示时 不仅要输入文件名 还要输入波段名称
giving me a length of two for sys.argv, let's go ahead
给我一个sys.argv的长度为2 让我们继续
and execute request stockget, which is a function inside of the request package
并执行请求股票 这是请求包中的一个函数
that will literally get some response from a server.
从字面上讲 这将从服务器获得一些响应
And the URL that I want to get is the exactly the same as before.
而我想要获取的URL与之前完全相同
https://itunes.apple.com/ search?entity=song&amp; limit=1&amp;
Https://itunes.apple.com/搜索？实体=歌曲；限制=1(&A；
term=previouslyweezer.
术语=以前的除草机
But let's make this program a little interactive
但让我们让这个节目更具互动性
and actually allow the human to specify at the command line what
并且实际上允许用户在命令行中指定
artists they'd like to search for.
他们想要寻找的艺术家
So I'm going to go ahead and close my quote early and just
所以我要提前结束我的报价
append using the concatenation operator as in the past, sys.argv bracket1.
像过去一样使用串联运算符sys.argv bracket1进行追加
And now, it actually be nice to store the response
现在 它实际上很好地存储了响应
from the server in a variable.
从服务器的变量中
So I'm going to go ahead and say response equals
所以我要继续说 回答等于
and to store all of the response that comes back
并存储所有返回的响应
from the server in a variable called response.
来自服务器的名为Response的变量中
Down here now, I'd like to just understand
现在 我想要了解的是
what the server's returning to me to make sure I know how next to proceed.
服务器返回给我的是什么 以确保我知道下一步如何继续
So this isn't going to be very pretty yet.
所以这还不会很美好
But I'm going to go and print out response.json,
但我要把答案打印出来 json
which ensures that the data I'm getting back is formatted on my screen
它可以确保我得到的数据在屏幕上被格式化
as exactly that, JSON, the same text format as we saw on my screen.
就是JSON 和我们在屏幕上看到的一样的文本格式
It's not a useful program yet.
它还不是一个有用的程序
I'm really just learning along the way.
我真的只是一路上学习
But let me go ahead now and increase the size of my terminal window
但是现在让我继续增加终端窗口的大小
and run Python of itunes.py and type in the name of a band like Weezer
运行itunes.py的Python 输入一个乐队的名字 比如Weezer
and hit Enter.
然后按回车键
And what we see on the screen formatted almost the same
我们在屏幕上看到的格式几乎相同
as before is exactly that same text.
与之前的文本完全相同
But what you'll see here is that this has been standardized now
但你会看到这已经标准化了
as a Python dictionary.
Python字典
What indeed Apple's returning is technically a JSON response,
实际上 苹果返回的是一个JSON响应
JavaScript Object Notation.
JavaScript对象表示法
But Python, the request library is converting it
但是Python 请求库正在转换它
to a Python dictionary which happens to use wonderfully coincidentally, almost
到Python字典 它碰巧使用了非常巧合的 几乎
the same syntax.
相同的语法
It uses curly braces to represent the dictionary here
它在这里用花括号表示字典
and a close curly brace to represent the end of it here.
和一个右花括号来表示它的结尾
For any lists therein, it uses a square bracket here
对于其中的任何列表 它在此处使用方括号
and a closed square bracket down here.
和一个封闭的方括号
It uses quotes-- single quotes in this case or equivalently double quotes
它使用了引号--这里是单引号 或者等效的双引号
to represent the keys in that dictionary.
来表示字典中的键
And after a colon, it stores the value of that key.
在冒号之后 它存储该键的值
And so you'll see that indeed we have a result count key whose value is 1,
所以你会看到我们确实有一个结果计数键 它的值是1
but then a more interesting Result key called results whose
但是还有一个更有趣的Result键 叫做results
value is this entire list of data.
值是整个数据列表
Now, honestly, this is such a big blob of text
老实说 这是一个很大的文本块
that it's going to take me forever to wrap my mind around what I'm seeing.
我得花很长时间才能理解我所看到的
So let me propose temporarily we use another library in Python that
所以让我暂时建议我们使用Python中的另一个库
will allow me to format my data a little more cleanly.
可以让我更清晰地格式化数据
It turns out that Python also comes with a special library called
原来Python还附带了一个特殊的库
JSON that allows you to manipulate JSON data
JSON允许您操作JSON数据
and even just printy print it that is formatted in a way that's going to be
甚至只是打印出来
way easier for you and I to understand.
更容易让你我理解
So let me go back to my code here.
让我回到我的代码
Let me shrink my terminal window.
让我缩小我的终端窗口
And let me propose that just temporarily again we do this.
让我再一次暂时地建议我们这样做
Let me import this additional library, JSON, which comes with Python.
让我导入这个额外的库JSON 它是随Python一起提供的
So I don't need to install it manually with pip.
所以我不需要使用pip手动安装它
And let me go ahead now and not just print out
现在让我继续 而不仅仅是打印出来
response.json which was that big blob of hard-to-understand text.
响应.json 这是一大团难以理解的文本
Let me go ahead and use one other function here called json.dumps
让我们继续使用另一个函数 这里称为json.dups
for dump string and pass to that function that response.json return
用于转储字符串 并传递给响应.json返回的函数
value.
价值
So again, I'm just introducing another function
所以 我再一次介绍另一个函数
who I claim has a purpose in life of pretty printing,
我认为他一生的目标都是漂亮的印刷品
nicely formatting on the screen the exact same information.
在屏幕上巧妙地格式化完全相同的信息
And I know this from the documentation having done this before.
我从以前做过这件事的文件中知道了这一点
But I'd like things to be nicely indented.
但我想让东西缩进得很好
And according to the documentation, if I pass in a named parameter of indent
根据文档 如果我传入一个命名参数缩进
equals 2, that's going to indent everything at least two spaces.
等于2 这将使所有内容缩进至少两个空格
I could do four or something else.
我可以做四个或其他的事情
But it's going to be enough to help me wrap my mind around what
但这将足以帮助我思考什么
the data is I'm getting back.
数据是我要回来了
Because again, I'm just learning along with you.
因为再说一次 我只是和你一起学习
So let me increase the size of my terminal window again.
因此 让我再次增加终端窗口的大小
Let me run Python of itunes.py.
让我运行itunes.py的Python
And again, let's search for Weezer and hit Enter.
再一次 让我们搜索Weezer并按Enter键
And now, notice it's still a little bit cryptic
现在 注意到它仍然有一点神秘
because there's a lot going on here.
因为这里发生了很多事情
But my gosh, I can totally read this more easily now.
但我的天啊 我现在完全可以更容易地阅读这个了
Notice now that I still see the first curly brace, which means hey,
请注意 现在我仍然看到第一个大括号 这意味着嘿
this is a dictionary in Python.
这是一本用Python语言编写的词典
A collection of keys and values.
键和值的集合
The first key is called result count.
第一个键称为结果计数
It happens to be displayed in double quotes now.
现在恰好用双引号显示
But that's just an issue of formatting.
但这只是一个格式问题
It could be double or single so long as we're consistent.
只要我们是一致的 就可以是双人或单人
The value of that key is one.
该密钥的值为1
Why?
为什么？
Well, I told the URL to only limit the responses to one Weezer song
嗯 我告诉URL将回复限制在一首Weezer歌曲上
so I've gotten a result set of one.
所以我得到了一个1的结果集
If I increase that limit, I could probably get more.
如果我增加这个限制 我可能会得到更多
Then the interesting part of this response is really the data itself.
那么 这个响应中有趣的部分实际上就是数据本身
Notice in the results key here, there's a really big value.
请注意 在这里的结果键中 有一个非常大的值
The value is a Python list as implied by this square bracket.
如方括号所示 该值是一个Python列表
What does this list contain?
这张单子里有什么？
Well, I know from skimming it earlier that this contains one dictionary.
嗯 我从之前的浏览中知道 这里面有一本词典
And that's why we see another curly brace here.
这就是为什么我们在这里看到另一个花括号
So again, if this gets a little more complicated,
所以 再说一次 如果事情变得更复杂
keep in mind that a dictionary is just a collection of key value pairs.
请记住 字典只是键值对的集合
And Python uses curly braces to indicate as much.
而Python使用大括号来表示这一点
It is perfectly reasonable for a dictionary
买一本词典是完全合理的
to be inside of another dictionary if the value of some key itself
如果某个键本身的值在另一个词典中
is another dictionary.
是另一本词典
So this is a common paradigm.
所以这是一个常见的范例
And even though it might seem a bit cryptic,
尽管这可能看起来有点神秘
it's just something that allows us to associate more keys with more value.
它只是允许我们将更多的键与更多的值相关联
Now, most of this information, I probably don't care about.
现在 这些信息中的大部分 我可能并不关心
For instance, according to Apple, the unique identifier for Weezer
例如 根据苹果公司的说法 Weezer的唯一标识符
is apparently 115,234.
显然是115,234
That might be useful if I'm making my own database
如果我要创建自己的数据库 这可能会很有用
and I want this to be searchable.
我希望这是可搜索的
But for today's purposes, all I care about is the name of the track,
但为了今天的目的 我只关心赛道的名字
otherwise called track name as key.
也称为轨道名称作为关键点
And the first song and only song because we limited it to one
第一首歌 也是唯一一首歌 因为我们把它限制在一首
that we got back from iTunes here is the song
我们从iTunes回来的是这首歌
that you might know by Weezer called Say It Ain't So.
你可能知道威泽叫“不是这样说”
So now, I have a bit of a clue if my goal here is to implement a program
现在 我有了一点线索 如果我的目标是实现一个计划
called itunes.py that doesn't just dump the response from the server,
名为itunes.py 它不仅转储来自服务器的响应
which is admittedly very cryptic--
诚然 这是非常神秘的--
but to print out all of the songs that iTunes has for the band called Weezer,
但要打印出iTunes为Weezer乐队准备的所有歌曲
maybe I can iterate over this somehow.
也许我可以以某种方式重复一下
So let me backtrack.
所以 让我回顾一下
Here's the key call track name.
这是关键呼叫跟踪名称
It is inside of a dictionary that is the value of results here.
在词典中 它就是这里结果的价值
So how can I go about getting this?
那么 我该如何着手拿到这个呢？
Well, let me go ahead and try this.
好吧 让我来试试这个
Let me go ahead and shrink my terminal window back down
让我继续缩小我的终端窗口
and let me propose now for one final flourish.
现在让我为最后一次盛大的表演做最后的提议
We don't just lazily print out the contents
我们不会只是懒洋洋地把内容打印出来
of that response because that's not interesting or pretty for anyone.
因为这对任何人来说都不有趣或不美观
Let's do this.
我们开始吧
Let me go ahead and create a new variable
让我们继续创建一个新变量
just for the sake of discussion called O for object.
仅为讨论起见 将对象称为O
And I'm going to go ahead and call o equals response.json just
我将继续调用o等于Response.json
to store that JSON response specifically in a variable called o,
要专门将该JSON响应存储在名为o的变量中
but I could name it anything I want.
但我可以给它起任何我想要的名字
And now, I'm going to do this.
现在 我要做这件事
For each result in that object's key called results,
对于该对象的键中的每个名为Results的结果
go ahead and print out that result's track name.
继续打印结果的曲目名称
And notice I have used exactly the same capitalization.
请注意 我使用的是完全相同的大写
Track name has a capital N. Result is all lowercase.
曲目名称为大写N 结果全部为小写
And let me rewind before we run the actual program.
在我们运行实际的程序之前 让我回顾一下
In line eight, we are making an HTTP request
在第八行中 我们发出了一个HTTP请求
using Python to the server just like you and I as humans type URLs
像你我一样在服务器上使用Python作为人类输入的URL
into a browser and hit Enter.
进入浏览器 然后按Enter键
This is the Python equivalent thereof.
这是等效于Python的代码
I am then on line 10 just grabbing from that variable that
然后我在第10行 从那个变量中获取
contains the server's response, the JSON object that I care about.
包含服务器的响应 即我关心的JSON对象
The thing between those curly braces at the very top and the bottom.
在最上面和最下面的花括号之间的东西
But because we've poked around and because I
而是因为我们四处打听 因为我
read the documentation earlier, I know that that object
读了前面的文档 我知道该对象
has a key called results.
有一个名为Results的键
And that results key again is a list.
而结果关键又是一个列表
Now, at the moment, that list contains only one song,
现在 这份名单上只有一首歌
Say It Ain't So, because I limited my response to one.
我不是这么说的 因为我的回答只有一个
But even so, my loop will work.
但即便如此 我的循环还是会起作用的
It's just going to iterate once.
它只会迭代一次
And each time through that loop, it's going
每次通过这个循环 它都会
to print the current result's track name.
若要打印当前结果的曲目名称 请执行以下操作
If I want to make this even more interesting,
如果我想让这件事更有趣
let me change this limit now from 1 to 50
现在让我将这个限制从1更改为50
so I'll at least get back 50 track names instead.
所以我至少可以取回50个曲目名称
Let me go ahead now and increase the size of my terminal once more
现在让我继续并再次增加我的终端的大小
and go ahead now and run Python of itunes.py searching again
现在继续并再次运行itunes.py的Python搜索
for a band like Weezer.
对于像威兹这样的乐队来说
And here we go.
现在我们开始吧
And voila, there are 50 songs that iTunes has for Weezer.
瞧 iTunes为Weezer准备了50首歌
And if we scroll back up to the top here,
如果我们向上滚动到顶部
we'll see that the very first one there is, indeed, Say It Ain't So.
我们会看到 第一个人 确实 也不是这样说的
But now, we got Undone--
但现在 我们被解开了--
The Sweater Song, Buddy Holly.
毛衣之歌 巴迪·霍莉
Apparently another rendition of Say It Ain't So perhaps
显然 另一首《Say It Ain Not》可能也是如此
from another album, another Buddy Holly undone, my name is Jonas, and so forth.
从另一张专辑 另一张巴迪·霍利未完成 我的名字是乔纳斯 等等
Questions now on this program which integrates Python with a real world
现在关于这个将Python与现实世界相结合的程序的问题
third party API?
第三方API？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, hi.
观众：是的 嗨
Can we use break instead of system.exit?
我们可以使用Break而不是Syst.Exit吗？
DAVID MALAN: Good question, but no.
大卫·马兰：问得好 但不是
Break again is used to break out of things like loops like we saw earlier.
Break Again用来打破我们之前看到的循环
Sys.exit is used to break out of the whole program itself.
使用Sys.Exit来突破整个程序本身
Use break for loops for now and use sys.exit to terminate
暂时使用BREAK FOR循环 并使用sys.exit终止
the whole program.
整个节目
Good question.
问得好
Other questions now on this program are others?
现在节目中的其他问题还有其他问题吗？
AUDIENCE: From where we bring the name of the key results?
观众：我们从哪里带来了关键成果的名字？
DAVID MALAN: From where do we get the name of the key?
大卫·马兰：我们从哪里得到钥匙的名字？
AUDIENCE: Results itself.
观众：结果本身
Yeah, and can we change the results, the name?
是啊 我们能不能更改结果 改名字？
DAVID MALAN: You cannot.
大卫·马兰：你不能
So we could in our program.
所以我们可以在我们的项目中
So the keys that come back in that JSON response, to be clear,
因此 明确地说 在JSON响应中返回的键
come from iTunes.Apple.com.
来自itunes.apple.com
Some team of engineers decided for us what all of those keys would be called,
一些工程师团队为我们决定了所有这些钥匙的名称
including track name, results, result count, and everything else.
包括曲目名称、结果、结果计数以及其他所有内容
You and I can absolutely store those same values in variables
你和我完全可以将这些相同的值存储在变量中
just like I'm doing here with O, just like I'm doing here with result.
就像我在这里对O所做的 就像我在这里对Result所做的那样
You can rename those keys anything you want using Python variables.
可以使用Python变量随心所欲地重命名这些关键点
But the JSON response is coming from that third party server.
但JSON响应来自该第三方服务器
Other questions.
其他问题
AUDIENCE: Yes, sir.
观众：是的 先生
So I have a question related to cowsay package.
因此 我有一个问题与牛仔套餐有关
So like, yes.
就像是 是的
So sir, what sort of ASCII graphics is it capable of putting?
那么 先生 它能提供什么样的ASCII图形呢？
DAVID MALAN: The cowsay package.
DAVID MALAN：牛仔套餐
I would refer you to the URL in the slides
我建议您参考幻灯片中的URL
earlier if only because it's more thorough.
因为这样更彻底
They have not just cows, but Tyrannosaurus rex's
他们不仅有牛 还有霸王龙
and several other animals as well.
还有其他几种动物
I should emphasize that this is not a package I suspect
我要强调的是 这不是一个包 我怀疑
you will use much in the real world.
你在现实世界中会用到很多东西
It's really just meant to be representative of the types of packages
它实际上只是代表了
you can install.
你可以安装
But allow me to refer to the documentation for what more is there.
但是 请允许我参考文件 了解更多的情况
But ASCII art is all we had before there were emojis, let alone GIFs and JPEGs
但在表情符号出现之前 我们只有ASCII艺术 更不用说GIF和JPEG了
and pings.
和ping
But it's what's is immortalized in cowsay.
但这是考赛镇的不朽之作
Well, allow me to transition us back now to one final capability of Python which
好 现在让我们回到Python的最后一个功能
is that you yourselves have the ability to make your own libraries.
就是你们自己有能力建立自己的图书馆
Up until now, we've been writing all of our functions in our one
到目前为止 我们一直在编写一个
file, Hello py and everything since.
文件 你好py和一切 因为.
And now that we've introduced modules in Python, random and statistics,
现在我们已经介绍了Python中的模块 随机和统计
we can import those that come with Python.
我们可以导入Python自带的
But that's other people's code as well.
但这也是别人的代码
And we've now used pip, this package manager to install
我们现在已经使用pip 这个包管理器来安装
third-party packages as well in the system
系统中的第三方软件包
and using other people's code still.
使用别人的代码
But to come full circle, what if you yourself
但是回到原点 如果你自己
find yourself implementing the same kinds of functions again and again,
发现自己一次又一次地实现相同的功能
or you find yourself opening up old programs,
或者你发现自己打开了旧的程序
copying and pasting code you wrote into new programs
复制并粘贴你写的代码到新程序中
because you have the same problem yet again?
因为你又遇到了同样的问题
A good practice would be to somehow bundle up that code you keep reusing
一个好的做法是以某种方式将您不断重用的代码捆绑起来
and make your own Python module or package.
创建你自己的Python模块或包
You can keep it local on your own Mac or PC or cloud server.
您可以将其保存在您自己的Mac或PC或云服务器上
Or you can go through the steps of actually bundling it up, making
或者你可以把它捆起来
it free and open source, and putting it on something like py, pi for others
它是免费的 开源的 把它放在像py pi这样的东西上
to use as well?
也可以使用？
OK, I'm going to go ahead and run code of sayings.py
好的 我继续运行sayings.py的代码
to create a brand new file called sayings.py which
创建一个名为sayings.py的全新文件
is going to be my own sayings module.
将会是我自己的语录模块
I'm going to define a couple of simple functions in there.
我将在其中定义几个简单的函数
I'm going to define a Hello function that's going
我将定义一个Hello函数 该函数
to take a name parameter as input.
要接受名称参数作为输入 请执行以下操作
And that function is simply going to print out
该函数将简单地打印出来
an F string that contains hello, comma, and then in curly braces,
一个F字符串 它包含Hello、逗号 然后用大括号括起来
whatever that person's name actually is.
不管那个人到底叫什么名字
Then I'm going to go ahead and define one other function,
然后我将继续定义另一个函数
a goodbye function, that has def, goodbye, also
一个告别功能 有def 再见 也
takes a name as its input.
接受名称作为其输入
And then that prints out by contrast and F
然后通过对比打印出来 然后F
string that says goodbye, comma, and then in curly braces, name.
表示再见的字符串 逗号 然后用大括号表示姓名
And now, just for good measure just so I can be sure
现在 只是为了好让我能确定
that these functions are working as expected,
这些功能正在按预期运行
I'm going to go ahead and define a main function in here
接下来 我将在这里定义一个主要函数
too just for the purposes of testing.
也只是为了测试的目的
And I'm going to go ahead and define a main function that
接下来 我将定义一个主要函数
simply does a couple of tests.
只是做了几个测试
For instance, it calls Hello of, quote, unquote, "world" shall we say?
例如 它叫Hello of 引用 引用 不引用 “world” 我们应该说吗？
And then it's going to call good bye of, quote, unquote, "world" as well.
然后它也会叫再见 引用 不引用 “世界”
And hopefully what I'll see on the screen then
希望我在屏幕上看到的是
is Hello world and Goodbye world when I run this program.
当我运行这个程序时 是Hello World和Goodbai World
Of course, as always, I need to explicitly tell
当然 像往常一样 我需要明确地告诉
Python to call that function.
来调用该函数
So I'm going to call main at the very bottom of this file.
所以我将在这个文件的最底部调用Main
All right, let's try it out.
好了 让我们试试看
Python of sayings.py, Enter.
Sayings.py的Python 回车
And indeed, I see Hello world and Goodbye world.
事实上 我看到了你好世界和再见世界
And so I think it's reasonable for me to assume
所以我认为我有理由认为
that these functions, albeit simple, are pretty correct at this point.
这些函数虽然简单 但在这一点上是相当正确的
But now, suppose that I want to use these functions as though I've indeed
但是现在 假设我想要使用这些函数 就好像我确实
created my own library, my own Python module and that makes available
创建了我自己的库 我自己的Python模块 这使得
a Hello function for me or anyone else who wants to use
Hello函数适用于我或任何其他想要使用
it or a Goodbye function as well.
它或再见功能也是如此
Well, let me go ahead and open up again say.py but start fresh.
好吧 让我继续 再次敞开心扉 比方说.py 但从头开始
And rather than have the cow say anything, let me go ahead
与其让牛说什么 不如让我继续说
and have my own library do the talking.
让我自己的图书馆来说话
So I'm going to go ahead and as before, import sys so that I
所以我要继续 像前面一样 导入sys以便我
have access to command line arguments.
可以访问命令行参数
And from my own module called sayings, I'm going to import Hello.
从我自己的名为Sayings的模块中 我将导入Hello
So because I created a file called sayings.py, I can say from sayings.
因此 因为我创建了一个名为sayings.py的文件 所以我可以从Sayings中得出结论
And it's inferred by Python that I mean sayings.py,
根据Python的推断 我的意思是Sayings.py
at least in this current directory.
至少在这个当前目录中
But I specifically ain't going to import just one of the functions
但我并不打算只导入其中一个函数
for now, namely Hello.
就目前而言 就是你好
And now, I can do something like this.
现在 我可以做这样的事情了
If the user obliges by giving me two command line arguments, which
如果用户愿意为我提供两个命令行参数
I can check by just checking the length of sys.argv,
我可以通过检查sys.argv的长度进行检查
I'm going to then go ahead and call this new Hello function passing
然后 我将继续调用这个新的Hello函数传递
as its input, sys.argvbracket1, which should hopefully be the person's name
作为它的输入 sys.argvbracket1 它应该是这个人的名字
which I'm going to expect them to type at the prompt.
我希望他们能在提示符下输入
So here we go.
所以我们开始吧
I'm going to go down to my terminal window,
我要去我的终端窗口
run Python of say.py and my own name because I want my own name to end up
运行Say.py和我自己的名字的Python 因为我希望我自己的名字以
in the command line arguments and therefore, be part of the Hello
在命令行参数中 因此成为Hello的一部分
so when I hit Enter in just a moment, I should hopefully see Hello,
因此 当我稍后按回车键时 我应该会看到Hello
comma, David.
逗号 大卫
So here we go, Enter.
所以我们开始吧 进入
And huh, I see Hello world, Goodbye world.
呵呵 我看到了你好世界 再见世界
And then I see Hello, David.
然后我看到了你好 大卫
So why is this happening?
那么 为什么会发生这种情况呢？
Well, it turns out even though I've done everything
好吧 事实证明即使我已经做了所有的事情
according to our own past practice, it's not really
根据我们自己过去的实践 它并不是真正的
the right way to go about calling main after all.
毕竟 调用Main的方法是正确的
If I'm blindly calling main here at the bottom of my file, that
如果我盲目地调用文件底部的Main
means whenever this file is loaded by Python, main is going to get called.
意味着每当该文件被Python加载时 main都将被调用
And unfortunately, that's true even if I'm importing this file or just
不幸的是 这是真的 即使我正在导入这个文件或者只是
a function from this file as I am here in my say.py program.
这个文件中的一个函数 因为我现在在我的say.py程序中
This is to say on line three here, when I say from sayings,
这是在这里的第三行 当我从谚语中说
import Hello, this effectively tells Python
IMPORT Hello 这实际上是在告诉Python
to go find that module, sayings.py, read it from top to bottom, left to right,
要找到那个模块sayings.py 请从上到下、从左到右阅读它
and then import specifically the Hello function.
然后专门导入Hello函数
Unfortunately by the time Python has read the file from top
不幸的是 在Python从顶部读取文件时
to bottom, left to right, that last line of code recall is to call main.
在底部 从左到右 最后一行代码调用是调用Main
Main gets called no matter what.
无论如何 Main都会被调用
So really, the right way to go about using a main function, which
所以真的 使用main函数的正确方法是
does solve that problem of ensuring that we can order our functions
确实解决了确保我们可以对我们的函数进行排序的问题
however we want, and all the functions will
任何我们想要的 所有的功能都将
be defined at the time they're invoked, I
是在调用它们时定义的 即
shouldn't be unconditionally calling main at the bottom of this
不应该无条件地在这个事件的底部调用Main
or really any of my programs.
或者实际上是我的任何程序
I should instead use this technique.
相反 我应该使用这种技术
I should say if__name__=="__main__", then and only then should you actually
我应该说如果__NAME__==“__Main__” 那么也只有到那时 你才应该真正
call main.
呼叫Main
Well, it turns out that this variable is a special symbol in Python, __name__.
好的 原来这个变量是Python中的一个特殊符号__NAME__
And notice that VS Code because of its font
请注意 由于其字体 VS代码
isn't quite showing those two underscores.
并没有显示出这两个下划线
But they're indeed there to the left and the right.
但他们确实在那里 在左边和右边
This is a special variable whose value is automatically set by Python to be,
这是一个特殊变量 其值由Python自动设置为
quote, unquote, "main" when you run a file from the command line
当您从命令行运行文件时 引号 不引号 “main”
as by running Python of sayings.py.
就像通过运行Sayings.py的Python一样
So watch what happens now with this additional conditional in sayings.py.
所以 现在看看sayings.py中的这个附加条件会发生什么
If I run Python of sayings.py, it still works as before because name will be
如果我运行sayings.py的Python 它仍然像以前一样工作 因为名称将是
automatically set to __main__ when I run this file using Python of sayings.py.
当我使用Sayings.py的Python运行此文件时 自动设置为__Main__
But notice this.
但请注意这一点
Name is not going to be set to, quote, unquote, "main."
名称不会设置为 引用 不引用 “Main”
It's going to be set to something else, technically the name of the module
它将被设置为其他名称 从技术上讲是模块的名称
when I instead import the file like I do here.
当我像这里一样导入文件时
So this highlighted line of code even though it
所以这段突出显示的代码行即使它
will cause Python to go find sayings.py, read it from top to bottom,
将导致Python查找sayings.py 从上到下阅读它
left to right, it's going to ignore the call to main this time
从左到右 它这次将忽略对Main的调用
because it's wrapped in that conditional.
因为它包含在条件句中
In this case, when I'm importing a file and not running it directly
在这种情况下 当我导入文件而不是直接运行它时
at the command line, main will not get called
在命令行中 不会调用main
by definition of that names value.
根据该Names值的定义
So let me go ahead and try this.
所以 让我继续试一试
Instead of running Python of sayings.py, which
而不是运行sayings.py的Python 它
is the module, which contains that conditional main,
是包含该条件Main的模块
let me go ahead here, run Python of say.py,
让我在这里继续 运行Say.py的Python
which is the program here before me that imports Hello from sayings.
这就是我面前的程序 它从Sayings中导入Hello
But because of that conditional, it's not
但由于这一条件 它不是
going to say Hello to anyone else except me in this case.
在这种情况下 我要向除我以外的任何人打招呼
All right, we're here at the end of our week.
好了 我们这周末就到了
It's only appropriate, I think, to import something other than Hello.
我认为 导入除Hello之外的其他内容才是合适的
Why don't I go ahead and import not Hello, but Goodbye from here.
为什么我不继续 输入的不是Hello 而是从这里开始的再见
Let me go ahead and call Goodbye instead of Hello.
让我继续说再见 而不是哈罗
And this time when I run Python of say.py,
这一次 当我运行Say.py的Python时
I'm not going to type my own name.
我不会打出我自己的名字
Allow me if I may to type in the whole world
请允许我在全世界范围内打字
so that our final sentiment today is Goodbye world.
所以我们今天的最后一句话是再见世界
Indeed, that's it for this week.
事实上 本周的情况就是这样
We will see you next time.
我们下次再见